<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Seanlnguyencom on DATA SCrIbers</title>
    <link>/tags/seanlnguyencom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Seanlnguyencom on DATA SCrIbers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/seanlnguyencom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Sleep Data with R</title>
      <link>/post/analyzing-sleep-data-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/analyzing-sleep-data-with-r/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been using the iOS Sleep Cycle app to track my sleeping since late 2014 and have accumulated quite a bit of information about my sleeping habits. I wanted to see if I could do some exploratory data analysis and try out some different packages to clean up and visualize my&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World’s Most Powerful Rocket</title>
      <link>/post/the-worlds-most-powerful-rocke/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-worlds-most-powerful-rocke/</guid>
      <description>SpaceX launched Falcon Heavy this week and I remembered how Elon Musk noted that it would have twice the thrust of any rocket currently in existence. I was intrigued by this statement and decided to look further and compare the thrusts of other rockets of the past and rockets that are planned in the future. Next I used rvest to read scrape the information extract the text and make it into a&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Starbucks Locations</title>
      <link>/post/mapping-starbucks-locations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mapping-starbucks-locations/</guid>
      <description>This is where I’ll be posting tutorials on how to use R and Rstudio to create some amazing graphics and visualizations. If you are completely new to R, don’t worry, I will post guides to explain how to start form scratch. This post assumes you have R and Rstudio installed and know how to install&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>