<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Favstatsnetlifycom on rscribers</title>
    <link>/tags/favstatsnetlifycom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Favstatsnetlifycom on rscribers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/favstatsnetlifycom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualzing Results of German Elections (2013 and 2017)</title>
      <link>/post/visualzing-results-of-german-e/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/visualzing-results-of-german-e/</guid>
      <description>Data Sources: https://www.govdata.de/web/guest/apps/-/details/bundestagswahl-2017 https://www.bundeswahlleiter.de/bundestagswahlen/2017/strukturdaten.html Settings, Packages and&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Temperature Rise in Stuttgart, Germany over Time</title>
      <link>/post/visualizing-temperature-rise-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/visualizing-temperature-rise-i/</guid>
      <description>This is a quick use-case of gganimate to visualize the rise of average temperature in my home town, Stuttgart, Germany. Get&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does Collinearity Influence Linear Regressions?</title>
      <link>/post/how-does-collinearity-influenc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-does-collinearity-influenc/</guid>
      <description>This is a short simulation study trying to figure out the impact of collinearity on linear regressions. Overview: Packages Simulation Function Simulate and Save Data Visualizing the Influence of Collinearity Standard Errors T-Statistic and P-Values B-Coefficients Animation Standardized Packages Load the necessary&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Tweets of the ECPR General Conference 2018</title>
      <link>/post/analyzing-tweets-of-the-ecpr-g/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/analyzing-tweets-of-the-ecpr-g/</guid>
      <description>This is a short notebook outlining the code used to scrape tweets related to the ECPR Conference 2018 in Hamburg. Packages Load the necessary&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Terror Attacks with Highcharter</title>
      <link>/post/mapping-terror-attacks-with-hi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mapping-terror-attacks-with-hi/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago someone asked me whether I could visualize the terror attacks of recent years in Europe. Here is an attempt to do exactly this. The code for this blogpost can be found in this GitHub Repository . Getting Started First I need data about terror attacks. For this I downloaded the Global Terrorism Database . Now in Rstudio, I load in the needed&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping your 2017 Geolocations</title>
      <link>/post/mapping-your-2017-geolocations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mapping-your-2017-geolocations/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I stumbled upon an instagram user who created a cool map of his geolocations. You can get his code here . I had to reproduce these cool maps myself and why not also make a blogpost while doing so? The code for this blogpost can be found in this GitHub Repository . Getting Started First I need my geolocation data. If you use Google and own an Android cell phone, you can download yours here .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do Arab Muslims think about ISIS (Daesh)?</title>
      <link>/post/what-do-arab-muslims-think-abo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/what-do-arab-muslims-think-abo/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my very first blogpost . Here I want to dive a little bit into how Arab Muslims see Daesh ( a term for ISIS often used by Arab speakers ). The data I will be using is from the Arab Barometer Wave 4 , released just a few weeks ago. I will also be using the Arab Barometer in the future because it has a lot of interesting questions asked, including a small sample size of Syrian&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>