<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Engineeringpivotalio on {data-scribers}</title>
    <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/tags/engineeringpivotalio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Engineeringpivotalio on {data-scribers}</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/tags/engineeringpivotalio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Keep-Alive Timeouts in the Cloud Foundry Networking Stack</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/understanding-keepalive-timeou/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/understanding-keepalive-timeou/</guid>
      <description>Setting up ingress routing is hard. Debugging problems when the routing tier is misconfigured can be even more challenging. At Pivotal, we often run into these types of issues. Below, we examine one such debugging session to understand both best practices in configuration and debugging&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quoted and unqouted template variables in Concourse CI</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/quoted-and-unqouted-template-v/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/quoted-and-unqouted-template-v/</guid>
      <description>A lesser known fact is that Concourse supports two different types of placeholders, quoted and unquoted. A variable, or placeholder, is specified using one of two different syntax forms: Pipeline example: The older version of placeholders, but still valid and working is quoted placeholders&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development of Greenplum for Kubernetes using Minikube</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/development-of-greenplum-for-k/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/development-of-greenplum-for-k/</guid>
      <description>Minikube is a single node Kubernetes environment designed for local development with local Kubernetes (K8s) and Docker support. Because of its portable nature, the development feedback cycle is faster with very minimum overhead&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eureka, Zuul, and Cloud Configuration - Local Development</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/eureka-zuul-and-cloud-configur/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/eureka-zuul-and-cloud-configur/</guid>
      <description>I went with a single repository for all of the components because simply, it is easier to work with. I would agree that eventually it would be better to move the Spring Cloud Configuration and API to be in their own separate repository and have all of the &amp;lsquo;local only&amp;rsquo; components have their own repository&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concourse as a Service and Multi-CPI</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/concourse-as-a-service-and-mul/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/concourse-as-a-service-and-mul/</guid>
      <description>As the Toolsmiths Team for Greenplum, we are tasked with doing everything in our power to enable other developers within the org&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Contribute to Golang!</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/lets-contribute-to-golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/lets-contribute-to-golang/</guid>
      <description>I want to share some particular insights I gained after attending the Contribution Workshop at GopherCon 2018. The purpose of this post is to allow you to be able to contribute to Golang as easily as possible and to provide you with some helpful tips. These tips are coalesced from multiple sources and my own troubleshooting. We are going to cover Gerrit..&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safely Upgrading PAS 2.2 → 2.3 with NSX-T Load Balancers</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/safely-upgrading-pas-22-23-wit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/safely-upgrading-pas-22-23-wit/</guid>
      <description>When customers with vSphere+NSX-T-based foundations upgrade PAS (Pivotal Application Service) from 2.2 to 2&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GiST Support In GPORCA</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/gist-support-in-gporca/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/gist-support-in-gporca/</guid>
      <description>Pivotal’s SQL Optimizer, GPORCA, does not handle GiST indexes, making any GPORCA generated plan extremely slow when the input grew large. In this blog post, we will look at what GiST indexes are, how we implemented them in GPORCA, and the resulting performance improvement&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frontend Contract Tests Without Magic Numbers</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/frontend-contract-tests-withou/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/frontend-contract-tests-withou/</guid>
      <description>We will explain how we fell into the magic number anti-pattern in our frontend tests. Then, we demonstrate how to use a contract-stub reader to avoid this&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s use Vault - Part 3</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/lets-use-vault-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/lets-use-vault-part-3/</guid>
      <description>We have now come to the final leg of our journey. We will be integrating Vault with Concourse CI and exploring some tooling that was built specifically to make your lives easier&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s use Vault - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/lets-use-vault-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/lets-use-vault-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This post provides a guideline of simplest commands that are required to setup vault locally for your team instead of having to wade through all of Hashicorp&amp;rsquo;s extensive documentation&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s use Vault - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/lets-use-vault-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/lets-use-vault-part-1/</guid>
      <description>There are comments in the config to explain the what and why of the properties. After vault is deployed we need to manually edit the ingress service. See the github issue below descrbing the reason for this change. This will show you the ingress service&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diagnosing Ruby Memory Issues in Cloud Foundry&#39;s API Server</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/diagnosing-ruby-memory-issues-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/diagnosing-ruby-memory-issues-/</guid>
      <description>Occasionally our end-users will use the platform in ways we might not have predicted, which results in unique and difficult-to-reproduce issues&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use &#39;tag_filter&#39; in &#39;git&#39; resources in Concourse CI</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/how-to-use-tagfilter-in-git-re/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/how-to-use-tagfilter-in-git-re/</guid>
      <description>This blog post will show how this resource type can be used to fetch a specific git tag from the repository&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install a TLS Certificate on vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) 6.7</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/how-to-install-a-tls-certifica/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/how-to-install-a-tls-certifica/</guid>
      <description>We want a green padlock on our VCSA&amp;rsquo;s web client; when we use our browser to navigate to our VCSA, we&amp;rsquo;d like it too look like the following: This blog posts describes the steps to follow in order to install a TLS certificate on a VCSA 6.7&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Pivotal contributes to the Development of PostgreSQL 11</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/how-pivotal-contributes-to-the/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/how-pivotal-contributes-to-the/</guid>
      <description>Not only is the PostgreSQL Project an awesome project with a thriving community, and it is fun to work with, in the long run this strategy has several advantages for us&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Regression Tests for Greenplum Database</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/create-regression-tests-for-gr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/create-regression-tests-for-gr/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s software development world, testing is a fundamental and necessary part of the entire lifecycle of the product&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Containers in Cloud Foundry? Here&#39;s How We Did It</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/windows-containers-in-cloud-fo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/windows-containers-in-cloud-fo/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a quick diagram, showing how these components interact. A close-up of Garden on Windows Server 2016 You’ll notice that the Garden components on a Windows Server 2016 Diego cell are the same as those on a Linux Diego cell&amp;hellip;except for the new plugins mentioned above&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Machine Learning to Recommend Driving Routes</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/scaling-machine-learning-to-re/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/scaling-machine-learning-to-re/</guid>
      <description>We built an app to predict potential earnings of a driver given his current location for next 8 hours in successive time intervals. The App also provided recommendations of next best pickup locations ranked based on driver preferences and behavior&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Failure is a part of the game</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/failure-is-a-part-of-the-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/failure-is-a-part-of-the-game/</guid>
      <description>Failure can come in a variety of avenues in life - career, love, and friendships to name a few. I’m choosing to highlight a few extra curricular projects to illustrate how success can come from failure&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking the Disk Speed of IaaSes</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/benchmarking-the-disk-speed-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/benchmarking-the-disk-speed-of/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post we record three metrics: And we record them for the following IaaSes: The table below summarizes our findings: AWS&amp;rsquo;s io1 storage is a &amp;ldquo;tunable&amp;rdquo; storage offering — you specify the number of IOPS you require&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event Sourcing with Kafka, RabbitMQ and JPA</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/event-sourcing-with-kafka-rabb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/event-sourcing-with-kafka-rabb/</guid>
      <description>We recently finished work on a system for a client in which we built an Event Source system. This application is a demo of the architecture we produced. This application was unique in that we implemented the backend with Apache Kafka, MongoDb and MySQL&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplify Deploying Kubernetes with Cloud Foundry Container Runtime</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/simplify-deploying-kubernetes-/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/simplify-deploying-kubernetes-/</guid>
      <description>The goal of Cloud Foundry Container Runtime is to simplify deploying and maintaining a Kubernetes cluster. It does a lot to alleviate the day-to-day burdens of an operator so they can focus on how to help their team execute. This is a walkthrough of how to install CFCR and deploy Kubernetes with it&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying BOSH VMs with IPv6 Addresses on vSphere</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/deploying-bosh-vms-with-ipv6-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/deploying-bosh-vms-with-ipv6-a/</guid>
      <description>BOSH is a VM orchestrator; a BOSH Director creates, configures, monitors, and deletes VMs. The BOSH Director interoperates with a number of IaaSes (Infrastructure as a Service), one of which is VMware vSphere, a virtualization platform. BOSH traditionally operates exclusively within the IPv4 networking space (i.e&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diagnosing performance issues with Java legacy apps on Pivotal Cloud Foundry</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/diagnosing-performance-issues-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/diagnosing-performance-issues-/</guid>
      <description>Table listing options ok! so given this situation how do you go about resolving it? First, It wasn&amp;rsquo;t an obvious situation for doing method-level profiling. So, we had to rule-out a few things that came to mind first: Network-related differences including Latency, bandwidth and route differences&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All I do is VIM VIM VIM</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/all-i-do-is-vim-vim-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/all-i-do-is-vim-vim-vim/</guid>
      <description>I assume you understand the difference between insert, visual and normal mode. So there are a few handy moves that I don&amp;rsquo;t know where to put. They are definitely beyond the basics&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>