<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Djnavarronet on {&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;data sc&lt;/span&gt;r&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;bers}</title>
    <link>/tags/djnavarronet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Djnavarronet on {&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;data sc&lt;/span&gt;r&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;bers}</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/djnavarronet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An &#39;academic&#39; discussion on Twitter</title>
      <link>/post/an-academic-discussion-on-twit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/an-academic-discussion-on-twit/</guid>
      <description>This post is my attempt to explain why. A now-infamous article was posted to the Chronicle of Higher Education a couple of weeks ago, discussing some of the issues surrounding the open science movement. I’m not going to link to the article itself because it’s a very bad take on what the open science movement should be about (and I think most people agreed on&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on participation</title>
      <link>/post/thoughts-on-participation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/thoughts-on-participation/</guid>
      <description>Very often I encounter students who are quiet, thoughtful and tend not to speak much. This is totally okay - not everyone in the classroom needs to be talking a&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A personal essay on Bayes factors</title>
      <link>/post/a-personal-essay-on-bayes-fact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-personal-essay-on-bayes-fact/</guid>
      <description>’Cause you’re hot then you’re cold You’re yes then you’re no You’re in then you’re out You’re up then you’re down You’re wrong when it’s right It’s black and it’s white - Katy Perry Or, in something closer to every day language: What’s not to love? Oh, you sweet summer&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 99-100: Small Steps</title>
      <link>/post/day-99100-small-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/day-99100-small-steps/</guid>
      <description>Not surprisingly most of the posts (about 75% of them) were written in the first half of the project. That’s partly the inevitable consequence of the novelty wearing off, but it also there have been a few other things that have come up along the way… One big thing that interacted with this 100Days project in positive way is my teaching&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 95-98: Press any key</title>
      <link>/post/day-9598-press-any-key/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/day-9598-press-any-key/</guid>
      <description>I’m getting to the very end of this package tryout exercise, and I suspect this will be the last post (other than perhaps a wrap up on Friday). It’s been a mildly annoying morning: I’ve done something to my foot, I’ve been awake since 4am, and somehow my twitter feed was full of people talking about Jordan Peterson 😒&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 82-94</title>
      <link>/post/day-8294/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/day-8294/</guid>
      <description>So this is a post about how I set up one part of my workflow. I feel nervous about it for two reasons: Yes, I realise that I’m setting myself up to feel bad. I should stop&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 67-81</title>
      <link>/post/day-6781/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/day-6781/</guid>
      <description>The motivation to face the fear is similarly straightforward: my R code runs too slowly for some of the problems I care about. It doesn’t come up that often, to be honest. Most problems I work on are small enough that it really doesn’t matter that my R code is slow. Other problems are standard enough that I can rely on other people’s compiled code to do all the work&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 63-66: Learning to skim</title>
      <link>/post/day-6366-learning-to-skim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/day-6366-learning-to-skim/</guid>
      <description>But everything is “under control” now, at least for a very expansive definition of “control”. The kids are keeping themselves occupied, I’ve responded to some overdue emails, and I’m making inroads into the Saturday morning laundry&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 55-62: R: The Boring Bits</title>
      <link>/post/day-5562-r-the-boring-bits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/day-5562-r-the-boring-bits/</guid>
      <description>The “random walk on CRAN” project, however, has been on hold for a bit - and in truth today’s post is a bit of a cop out because there’s no package here at all and barely anything resembling code. Instead, it’s some initial thoughts about how to revisit some of my teaching material. For today though, I have a different goal… But still, it’s nice to think about what we might do if we have more&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 51-52: Kabling</title>
      <link>/post/day-5152-kabling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/day-5152-kabling/</guid>
      <description>Not wanting to give away the list of things that might appear on bingo cards (or alternatively, not actually having written all the items yet!) I’ll need to find some content to use for this post… Oh yes little network, you had me at “hello”. Here’s what we get: It’s a good start, but it’s all structure and no style! No, wait, that doesn’t work. Why? There we&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 47-50: Paletter</title>
      <link>/post/day-4750-paletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/day-4750-paletter/</guid>
      <description>Okay! It’s a Thursday evening. Solo parenting is over. My partner is back in town. The kids are in bed. Tina Turner is playing over the wireless. I’m the last one awake. Time for an R post, because that’s just the kind of girl I&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 39-46</title>
      <link>/post/day-3946/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/day-3946/</guid>
      <description>This series of posts has been on hold for the last few days because I’ve been solo parenting and had a few deadlines at work. I have no idea how single parents&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 38: Algorithmic complexity</title>
      <link>/post/day-38-algorithmic-complexity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/day-38-algorithmic-complexity/</guid>
      <description>can be produced with a very short R program: whereas a random-looking string like However, if I use R as the compressing language, there is a very short program that produces it: All of which is by way of background. And calling it… Not surprisingly, complexity increases as a sequence becomes longer, even if it’s the the same symbol being&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 36-37: Concerned DALEX</title>
      <link>/post/day-3637-concerned-dalex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/day-3637-concerned-dalex/</guid>
      <description>I was working on a longer post continuing the metaprogramming series, and realised I wasn’t going to get it done this evening. But it’s been a couple of days since I tried out something new, so I resorted to the twitters to find&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>