<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vuorrenetlifycom on rscribers</title>
    <link>/tags/vuorrenetlifycom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vuorrenetlifycom on rscribers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/vuorrenetlifycom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Access Mandates</title>
      <link>/post/open-access-mandates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/open-access-mandates/</guid>
      <description>Here are some notes on how the six features can be achieved using nothing else but “stuff on the internet”. I won’t provide detailed arguments, but just quick notes on how each of these features can already be implemented with minimal cost to researchers. This is a no-brainer. Many of us are already posting “pre-prints” (versions of manuscript that have not been accepted for publication) on many of the pre-print servers supported by the&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Estimation of Signal Detection Models, Part 4</title>
      <link>/post/bayesian-estimation-of-signal-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bayesian-estimation-of-signal-/</guid>
      <description>However, we almost always want to discuss our inference about the population, not individual subjects. Further, if we wish to discuss individual subjects, we should place them in the context of other subjects. A multilevel (aka hierarchical, mixed) model accomplishes these goals by including population- and subject-level parameters. Here’s the brms syntax we used for estimating the model for a single participant: We can then estimate the model as&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Estimation of Signal Detection Models, Part 3</title>
      <link>/post/bayesian-estimation-of-signal-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bayesian-estimation-of-signal-/</guid>
      <description>This post is the third part in a series of blog posts on Signal Detection models: In the first part, I described how to estimate the equal variance Gaussian SDT (EVSDT) model for a single participant, using Bayesian (generalized linear and nonlinear) modeling techniques. In the second part, I described how to estimate the equal variance Gaussian SDT model for multiple participants simultaneously, using hierarchical Bayesian&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Estimation of Signal Detection Models, Part 2</title>
      <link>/post/bayesian-estimation-of-signal-/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bayesian-estimation-of-signal-/</guid>
      <description>This post is the second part of a series of three blog posts: In the first part, I described how to estimate the equal variance Gaussian SDT (EVSDT) model for a single participant, using Bayesian (generalized linear and nonlinear) modeling techniques. In the third part, I describe how to estimate the unequal variance Gaussian SDT model as a nonlinear Bayesian&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Estimation of Signal Detection Models, Part 1</title>
      <link>/post/bayesian-estimation-of-signal-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bayesian-estimation-of-signal-/</guid>
      <description>This post is the first part of a series of three blog posts: In the second part, I describe how to estimate the equal variance Gaussian SDT model for multiple participants simultaneously, using hierarchical Bayesian models. In the third part, I describe how to estimate the unequal variance Gaussian SDT model as a hierarchical nonlinear Bayesian&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharing R products</title>
      <link>/post/sharing-r-products/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sharing-r-products/</guid>
      <description>Sharing R data (.rda) and R code (.R) files is becoming more common in the social sciences. Brilliant! However, I think that the process of sharing R products could be made significantly easier for everyone involved if people followed one simple piece of advice: Don’t set R’s working directory from within an R script. Sharing data is easy, because users can put the data wherever they want on their computers, and use it from&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIPS 2017 Conference Tweets</title>
      <link>/post/sips-2017-conference-tweets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sips-2017-conference-tweets/</guid>
      <description>The timeline of tweets reveals that SIPSers were most active on Twitter on Monday, and there’s a clear spike of activity at 6pm on Monday. Here are the top 5 SIPS non-retweets. Here are the top hashtags people used with the SIPS hashtag. And finally the obligatory graph: Arrows represent tweets going from someone to someone&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Correlated Psychological Variables, Uncertainty, and Bayesian Estimation</title>
      <link>/post/correlated-psychological-varia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/correlated-psychological-varia/</guid>
      <description>Assessing the correlations between psychological variabless, such as abilities and improvements, is one essential goal of psychological science. However, psychological variables are usually only available to the researcher as estimated parameters in mathematical and statistical models. The parameters are often estimated from small samples of observations for each research participant, which results in uncertainty (aka sampling error) about the participant-specific&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing varying effects&#39; posteriors with joyplots</title>
      <link>/post/visualizing-varying-effects-po/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/visualizing-varying-effects-po/</guid>
      <description>However, to make the figure more Unknown Pleasures-y, you’ll need to modify the theme a little bit: Well, there you go. Have&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>