<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Noahlandesbergcom on DATA SCrIbers</title>
    <link>/tags/noahlandesbergcom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Noahlandesbergcom on DATA SCrIbers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/noahlandesbergcom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>8 Analytics Books I Read in 2017</title>
      <link>/post/8-analytics-books-i-read-in-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/8-analytics-books-i-read-in-20/</guid>
      <description>This year I made a concerted effort to read more books related to my interests in analytics, math, and data science. I had the pleasure of reading most of these books with a group of people at work, and we met on a regular basis to discuss and gab. These books are casual, and not meant to be as strictly educational (or tedious) as reading a textbook. Without further ado&amp;hellip; here are 8 analytics books I read this year: Dataclysm explores the data underlying human connections and</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing rhymer</title>
      <link>/post/introducing-rhymer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/introducing-rhymer/</guid>
      <description>For example, I’ve been enjoying rewriting nursery rhymes: The package includes additional functions to find other related words, including: And of course, much thanks</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking in Systems with DiagrammeR</title>
      <link>/post/thinking-in-systems-with-diagr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/thinking-in-systems-with-diagr/</guid>
      <description>One of the concepts introduced in the book is stock and flow diagrams that represent basic systems. The first diagram in the book shows a basic stock with an inflow and outflow. Meadows goes on to describe the stock-and-flow diagram: stocks are shown as boxes, and flows as arrow-headed “pipes” leading into or out of the stocks. The small T on each flow signifies a “faucet;” it can be turned higher or lower, on or</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building my website with Blogdown</title>
      <link>/post/building-my-website-with-blogd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/building-my-website-with-blogd/</guid>
      <description>When building this site, the two resources I consulted were: It might seem complicated, but with some coffee and tenacity whole thing can be done in an</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>