<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Batteriesnotincludedrbindio on {data-scribers}</title>
    <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/tags/batteriesnotincludedrbindio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Batteriesnotincludedrbindio on {data-scribers}</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/tags/batteriesnotincludedrbindio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>dockerterm</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/dockerterm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/dockerterm/</guid>
      <description>As seen in the clip above, this initial proof of concept works well, at least on my machine. There are some definite drawbacks and limitations that need to be addressed, but for the most part, I’m pleased with the initial functionality&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The FutuRe is Bright</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/the-future-is-bright/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/the-future-is-bright/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been a (usually) silent observer of the rstats community via twitter. Occasionally I’ll jump in and share thoughts or retweet something I found particularly helpful or inspiring, but for the most part I just sit back and observe. I’ve always admired the fact that, online, the R community seems helpful, kind, and aware of one another&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ad Hoc Testing</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/ad-hoc-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/ad-hoc-testing/</guid>
      <description>Unit tests are typically designed with a set function name in mind - that is, the function being tested will always have the same name, it may just have an updated definition. However, when testing interactively, I find that sometimes I want to test two different versions of a function to compare their behavior&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping Friends</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/scraping-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/scraping-friends/</guid>
      <description>Now that we’re set up and ready to go, let’s take a moment to think through what we need to do in order to build out this data set. 1. Download all scripts with identifying season and episode data 2. Parse all scripts into speaker and line 3. Clean up any errors 4. Celebrate good times Seems simple enough&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>