<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nitingupta2githubio on rscribers</title>
    <link>/tags/nitingupta2githubio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nitingupta2githubio on rscribers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/nitingupta2githubio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How would you bet? Lessons from a Biased Coin Flipping Experiment</title>
      <link>/post/how-would-you-bet-lessons-from/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-would-you-bet-lessons-from/</guid>
      <description>Recently I listened to a podcast featuring Victor Haghani of Elm Partners , who described a fascinating coin-flipping experiment. The experiment was designed to be played for 30 minutes by participants in groups of 2-15 in university classrooms or office conference rooms, without consulting each other or the internet or other resources. To conduct the experiment, a custom web app was built for placing bets on a simulated coin with a 60% chance of coming up&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investment Strategy Diversification</title>
      <link>/post/investment-strategy-diversific/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/investment-strategy-diversific/</guid>
      <description>By all conventional and even some unconventional measures, the US stock market is trading way beyond historical valuation averages and is closer to all time highs. Passive stock index investors have enjoyed a period of extraordinary gains in one of the longest running bull markets. No other major asset class has come close in the last 7&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luck in Rebalance Timing</title>
      <link>/post/luck-in-rebalance-timing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/luck-in-rebalance-timing/</guid>
      <description>An important and often overlooked topic was raised by Corey Hoffstein at NewFound Research. Here are his first couple of tweets on that&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Analysis of Amazon Shareholder Letters</title>
      <link>/post/text-analysis-of-amazon-shareh/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/text-analysis-of-amazon-shareh/</guid>
      <description>Amazon is led by its charismatic founder and CEO, Jeff Bezos, who is widely hailed as one of the top visionaries of this era. At the end of the fiscal year in March, Amazon publishes a letter to shareholders written by Bezos, in which he summarises his thoughts, business and management philosophy. While reading these letters, among other things that strikes is Bezos’ clarity of thought, expressed in a concise and easy to comprehend way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Predictive Typing Model</title>
      <link>/post/building-a-predictive-typing-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/building-a-predictive-typing-m/</guid>
      <description>Everyone using a smartphone or a mobile device has used an onscreen smart keyboard that tries to predict the next set of words that the user might want to type. Typically, upto 3 words are predicted, which are displayed in a row at the top of the&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best batsmen in cricket at present</title>
      <link>/post/best-batsmen-in-cricket-at-pre/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/best-batsmen-in-cricket-at-pre/</guid>
      <description>Who’re the best batsmen in cricket today? Is there a way to define a set of objective criteria that provides an unbiased conclusion? In my last post , I selected a list of top batsmen in the history of cricket, by simply filtering all batsmen who have had a career batting average of 50 or more in any&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top batsmen in cricket</title>
      <link>/post/top-batsmen-in-cricket/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/top-batsmen-in-cricket/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post , I used data from Statsguru and looked at a brief history of cricket with respect to debut years and career spans of players. In this post, I use detailed player statistics from the same dataset to select top batsmen who have played this game. Distribution of matches played by all players Let’s take a look at the summary statistics of number of matches played by all players in each format of the&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A brief history of cricket</title>
      <link>/post/a-brief-history-of-cricket/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-brief-history-of-cricket/</guid>
      <description>Since early childhood, I have been a big fan of cricket. Some of my earliest childhood memories are watching the game along with my loved ones in India. As much as I can recall, the first series I saw was between India and the West Indies during the early 80s, on a black and white TV&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>