<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tojyousogithubio on rscribers</title>
    <link>/tags/tojyousogithubio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tojyousogithubio on rscribers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/tojyousogithubio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>When is the best time to play your wildcard?</title>
      <link>/post/when-is-the-best-time-to-play-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/when-is-the-best-time-to-play-/</guid>
      <description>I love football. It’s the greatest sport ever. And I mean real football not what is played in America. I wanted to be a footballer for ages but now I’m 28 and I still haven’t signed any multi million pound contracts, I think I’ll give up on that. The next best thing is watching football and I do that, a lot. Particularly the red half of Manchester as quite a few Londoners do :p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monthly Report: May 2017</title>
      <link>/post/monthly-report-may-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/monthly-report-may-2017/</guid>
      <description>This is my review of May 2017. I hope to make this a regular occurrence and I want to publish something at the end of each month. I’ve been putting this off for quite some time because it’s not where I want it to be but I’m just going ahead and doing it. You can call this the MVP. In the coming months, it will get better and I will add more&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/post/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/about-me/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my site! I created this site to capture my interests in one place. You&amp;rsquo;ll read about my quantified self journey, my football interests (and fantasy league) and how I am learning to play with data through #rstats. Want to get in contact? Hit me up one of the social media buttons below my name at the top of the page. Thanks for&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysing the words I write in my journal</title>
      <link>/post/analysing-the-words-i-write-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/analysing-the-words-i-write-in/</guid>
      <description>One area of my quantified journey that I have struggled with tracking is my mood and feelings. I’ve tried nomie which is great, I’ve tried a couple of other mood tracker apps but after a while I lose motivation to record these things. They felt a bit meaningless because I had to record my mood at random points throughout the day, but I needed more&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>