<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Asch3ttinetlifycom on rscribers</title>
    <link>/tags/asch3ttinetlifycom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Asch3ttinetlifycom on rscribers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/asch3ttinetlifycom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My first experience with text mining</title>
      <link>/post/my-first-experience-with-text-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/my-first-experience-with-text-/</guid>
      <description>The first step was to quantify how often words were used across the 34 chapters of the novel, to have an initial idea of the content. So, I counted the number of occurrences for each word and selected only the most common ones (i.e., occurring at least 100 times). “How a human being could have attempted such a book as the present without committing suicide before he had finished a dozen chapters, is a&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Holidays!</title>
      <link>/post/happy-holidays/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/happy-holidays/</guid>
      <description>A simple white background was not enough. We needed something more appropriate for this period of the year… ah, yes! Snow! The end result is a big flat face fluctuating in the air, like a spooky and ominous reminder of our mortality even in these days of opulence. I only want the best for my furry boy and his floating flat face, so I modified my initial script and added van der Laken’s&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attractive Attractor</title>
      <link>/post/attractive-attractor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/attractive-attractor/</guid>
      <description>My first post is going to be trivial but, I think, quite mesmerizing. This is sweet, but something is missing… perhaps there are not enough points. Let’s use 10,000,000! That’s more like it. Now let’s make another attractor, using 10,000,000 magenta points. I’ve got an idea: let’s make a few more, and then overlay them! Fantastic. This took a long time but… totally worth the effort! In case you want to waste countless hours hunting for the perfect Clifford attractor, here is the&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>