<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jamesuanhorocom on {data-scribers}</title>
    <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/tags/jamesuanhorocom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jamesuanhorocom on {data-scribers}</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/tags/jamesuanhorocom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Should you perform logistic regression on a dichotomized continuous variable when you have access to the continuous variable? I&#39;m not sure.</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/should-you-perform-logistic-re/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/should-you-perform-logistic-re/</guid>
      <description>A standard situation in education or medicine is we have a continuous measure, but then we have cut-points on those continuous measures that are clinically/practically significant. An example is BMI where I hear 30 matters. You may have an achievement test with 70 as the pass score&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two group mean and variance comparisons</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/two-group-mean-and-variance-co/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/two-group-mean-and-variance-co/</guid>
      <description>Someone asked an interesting question on Cross Validated recently about comparing the means and variances of two groups&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling the error variance to account for heteroskedasticity</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/modeling-the-error-variance-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/modeling-the-error-variance-to/</guid>
      <description>One of the assumptions that comes with applying OLS estimation for regression models in the social sciences is homoskedasticity, I prefer constant error variance (it also goes by spherical disturbances)&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulating data from regression models</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/simulating-data-from-regressio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/simulating-data-from-regressio/</guid>
      <description>My preferred approach to validating regression models is to simulate data from them, and see if the simulated data capture relevant features of the original data. A basic feature of interest would be the mean. I like this approach because it is extendable to the family of generalized linear models (logistic, Poisson, gamma, ..&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using binary regression software to model ordinal data as a multivariate GLM</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/using-binary-regression-softwa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/using-binary-regression-softwa/</guid>
      <description>I have read that the most common model for analyzing ordinal data is the cumulative link logistic model, coupled with the proportional odds assumption. Essentially, you treat the outcome as if it were the categorical manifestation of a continuous latent variable&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using glmer() to perform Rasch analysis</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/using-glmer-to-perform-rasch-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/using-glmer-to-perform-rasch-a/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in the relationship between ordinal regression and item response theory (IRT) for a few months now. There are several helpful papers on the topic, here are some randomly picked ones 1 2 3 4 5, and a book&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Chi-Square test of close fit in covariance-based SEM</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/a-chisquare-test-of-close-fit-/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/a-chisquare-test-of-close-fit-/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: If you can assume close fit for the RMSEA, there is no reason why you cannot for a Chi-Square test in SEMs&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misspecification and fit indices in covariance-based SEM</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/misspecification-and-fit-indic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/misspecification-and-fit-indic/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: If you have good measurement quality, conventional benchmarks for fit indices may lead to bad decisions. Additionally, global fit indices are not informative for investigating misspecification. I am working with one of my professors, Dr&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little&#39;s MCAR test at different sample sizes</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/littles-mcar-test-at-different/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/littles-mcar-test-at-different/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: Little&amp;rsquo;s MCAR test is unable to tell data that are MCAR from data that are MAR in small samples, but maintains the nominal error rate when null is true across a wide range of sample sizes&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theil-Sen regression in R</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/theilsen-regression-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/theilsen-regression-in-r/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: When performing a simple linear regression, if you have any concern about outliers or heterosedasticity, consider the Theil-Sen estimator. A simple linear regression estimator that is not commonly used or taught in the social sciences is the Theil-Sen estimator&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear regression with violation of heteroskedasticity with small samples</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/linear-regression-with-violati/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/linear-regression-with-violati/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: In small samples, the wild bootstrap implemented in the R hcci package is a good bet when heteroskedasticity is a concern. Today while teaching the multiple regression lab, I showed the class the standardized residuals versus standardized predictor plot SPSS lets you produce. It is the plot we typically use to assess homoskedasticity&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the interpretation of regression coefficients</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/on-the-interpretation-of-regre/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/on-the-interpretation-of-regre/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: We should interpret regression coefficients for continuous variables as we would descriptive dummy variables, unless we intend to make causal claims. I am going to be teaching regression labs in the Fall, and somehow, I stumbled onto Gelman and Hill&amp;rsquo;s Data analysis using regression and multilevel/hierarchical models&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>