<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning on rscribers</title>
    <link>/categories/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine Learning on rscribers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science in Mental Health</title>
      <link>/post/data-science-in-mental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-science-in-mental-health/</guid>
      <description>I came across two articles recently that I thought spoke to each other in an interesting way. The first was a New York Times piece about the failings of data science firms who try to identify school shootings before they happen by social media&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving beyond pattern-based analysis</title>
      <link>/post/moving-beyond-patternbased-ana/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/moving-beyond-patternbased-ana/</guid>
      <description>This is the sixth and the last blog post in the series introducing GeoPAT 2 - a software for pattern-based spatial and temporal analysis . In the previous one we presented the pattern-based spatial segmentation - a method for creating regions of homogenous&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how should I get started with R?</title>
      <link>/post/how-should-i-get-started-with-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-should-i-get-started-with-/</guid>
      <description>Here’s some evergreen advice from David Robinson: When you’ve written the same code 3 times, write a function When you’ve given the same in-person advice 3 times, write a blog post - David Robinson (@drob) November 9,&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yet Another Caret Workshop</title>
      <link>/post/yet-another-caret-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/yet-another-caret-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Intro Yesterday I gave a workshop on applied predictive modelling1 with caret at the 1st LSE Computational Social Science hackathon. Organiser privileges. I put together some introductory code and started a simple GitHub repo for the participants, so I thought I’d share it here as well. This is not supposed to cover all aspects of caret (plus there is already this), but more of a starter-pack for those who might be migrating from Python or another machine learning library like&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YMMV: non-profit data science</title>
      <link>/post/ymmv-nonprofit-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ymmv-nonprofit-data-science/</guid>
      <description>(YMMV = your mileage may vary) Introduction Feeling inspired by some recent data science collaborations, on Friday I released the following tweet into the wild: want to build data science experience? reach out to a local non-profit you&amp;#39;re interested in, and ask them if you can volunteer with data collection, cleaning, and basic analysis and reporting. you get experience, the NPO gets a product they desperately need, and everyone wins. - Jesse Mostipak (@kierisi) March 30,&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yet Another Titanic Solve</title>
      <link>/post/yet-another-titanic-solve/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/yet-another-titanic-solve/</guid>
      <description>Objectives Read in the dataset Train-Test Split Missing values analysis EDA Target Variable Predictor Variables Univariate &amp;amp; Bivariate Multivariate Analyses Data Preparation Missing Values Imputation Derived Variables Final Data Review Modeling Extreme Gradient Boosting Elastinet k-NN SVM C5.0 Averaged Neural Networks Conditional Inference Random Forests Compare models Test Set Evaluation Create test set Predict test results Kaggle Performance tl;dr: Another titanic&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpretable Machine Learning with iml and mlr</title>
      <link>/post/interpretable-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/interpretable-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Machine learning models repeatedly outperform interpretable, parametric models like the linear regression model. The gains in performance have a price: The models operate as black boxes which are not interpretable. Fortunately, there are many methods that can make machine learning models&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training Courses for mlr</title>
      <link>/post/training-courses-for-mlr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/training-courses-for-mlr/</guid>
      <description>The mlr: Machine Learning in R package provides a generic, object-oriented and extensible framework for classification, regression, survival analysis and clustering for the statistical programming language R. The package targets practitioners who want to quickly apply machine learning algorithms, as well as researchers who want to implement, benchmark, and compare their new methods in a structured environment. We are happy to announce that we now offer training courses specialized on&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supervised vs. Unsupervised Learning</title>
      <link>/post/supervised-vs-unsupervised-lea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/supervised-vs-unsupervised-lea/</guid>
      <description>Outcome Supervision Yesterday I was part of an introductory session on machine learning and unsurprisingly, the issue of supervised vs. unsupervised learning came up. In social sciences, there is a definite tendency for the former; there is more or less always a target outcome or measure that we want to optimise the performance of our models for. This reminded me of a draft that I had written the code a couple of months ago but for some reason never converted into a blog post until&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Conflict Duration with (gg)plots using Keras</title>
      <link>/post/predicting-conflict-duration-w/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/predicting-conflict-duration-w/</guid>
      <description>An Unlikely Pairing Last week, Marc Cohen from Google Cloud was on campus to give a hands-on workshop on image classification using TensorFlow. Consequently, I spent most of my time thinking about how I can incorporate image classifiers in my work. As my research is primarily on forecasting armed conflict duration, it’s not really straightforward to make a connection between the&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Rtus wins Munich Re Datathon with mlr</title>
      <link>/post/team-rtus-wins-munich-re-datat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/team-rtus-wins-munich-re-datat/</guid>
      <description>On the weekend of November 17. - 19. five brave data-knights from team “Rtus and the knights of the data.table” took on the challenge to compete in a datathon organized by Munich Re in its Munich-based innovation lab. Team Rtus was formed in April this year by a bunch of statistics students from LMU with the purpose to prove their data-skills in competitions with other teams from various&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated and Unmysterious Machine Learning in Cancer Detection</title>
      <link>/post/automated-and-unmysterious-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/automated-and-unmysterious-mac/</guid>
      <description>I get bored from doing two things: i) spot-checking + optimising parameters of my predictive models and ii) reading about how &amp;lsquo;black box&amp;rsquo; machine learning (particularly deep learning) models are and how little we can do to better understand how they learn (or not learn, for example when they take a panda bear for a&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenML Workshop 2017</title>
      <link>/post/openml-workshop-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/openml-workshop-2017/</guid>
      <description>What is OpenML? The field of Machine Learning has grown tremendously over the last years, and is a key component of data-driven science. Data analysis algorithms are being invented and used every day, but their results and experiments are published almost exclusively in journals or separated repositories. However, data by itself has no value. It’s the ever-changing ecosystem surrounding data that gives it&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Análisis de Varianza (ANOVA)</title>
      <link>/post/an%C3%A1lisis-de-varianza-anova/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/an%C3%A1lisis-de-varianza-anova/</guid>
      <description>Curso intersemestral impartido en el verano de 2017 por&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>shinyMlr</title>
      <link>/post/shinymlr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/shinymlr/</guid>
      <description>shinyMlr is a web application, built with the R-package “shiny” that provides a user interface for mlr. By wrapping the main functionalities of mlr into our app, as well as implementing additional features for data visualisation and data preprocessing, we built a widely usable application for your day to day machine learning tasks, which we would like to present to you&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Analysis of Amazon Shareholder Letters</title>
      <link>/post/text-analysis-of-amazon-shareh/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/text-analysis-of-amazon-shareh/</guid>
      <description>Amazon is led by its charismatic founder and CEO, Jeff Bezos, who is widely hailed as one of the top visionaries of this era. At the end of the fiscal year in March, Amazon publishes a letter to shareholders written by Bezos, in which he summarises his thoughts, business and management philosophy. While reading these letters, among other things that strikes is Bezos’ clarity of thought, expressed in a concise and easy to comprehend way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most Popular Learners in mlr</title>
      <link>/post/most-popular-learners-in-mlr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/most-popular-learners-in-mlr/</guid>
      <description>For the development of mlr as well as for an “machine learning expert” it can be handy to know what are the most popular learners used. Not necessarily to see, what are the top notch performing methods but to see what is used “out there” in the real world. Thanks to the nice little package cranlogs from metacran you can at least get a slight estimate as I will show in the&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallel benchmarking with OpenML and mlr</title>
      <link>/post/parallel-benchmarking-with-ope/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/parallel-benchmarking-with-ope/</guid>
      <description>With this post I want to show you how to benchmark several learners (or learners with different parameter settings) using several data sets in a structured and parallelized fashion. For this we want to use batchtools. The data that we will use here is stored on the open machine learning platform openml.org and we can download it together with information on what to do with it in form of a&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenML tutorial at useR!2017 Brussels</title>
      <link>/post/openml-tutorial-at-user2017-br/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/openml-tutorial-at-user2017-br/</guid>
      <description>What is OpenML? Conducting research openly and reproducibly is becoming the gold standard in academic research. Practicing open and reproducible research, however, is hard. OpenML.org (Open Machine Learning) is an online platform that aims at making the part of research involving data and analyses&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mlr Google Summer of Code 2017</title>
      <link>/post/mlr-google-summer-of-code-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mlr-google-summer-of-code-2017/</guid>
      <description>We are happy to announce that we applied for a another Google Summer of Code project in 2017. Operator Based Machine Learning Pipeline Construction We aim to change the way we are currently doing data preprocessing in mlr. Have a look at the proposal linked above for more details. If you are interested in doing this project, have a look at the tests and&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>