<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fharrellcom on {&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;data sc&lt;/span&gt;r&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;bers}</title>
    <link>/tags/fharrellcom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fharrellcom on {&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;data sc&lt;/span&gt;r&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;bers}</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/fharrellcom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>In Machine Learning Predictions for Health Care the Confusion Matrix is a Matrix of Confusion</title>
      <link>/post/in-machine-learning-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/in-machine-learning-prediction/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning (ML) has already transformed e-commerce, web search, advertising, finance, intelligence, media, and more. ML is becoming ubiquitous and its centripetal gravity draws health care into the&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Methods Discussion Site</title>
      <link>/post/data-methods-discussion-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-methods-discussion-site/</guid>
      <description>I have learned more from Twitter than I ever thought possible, from those I follow and from my followers. Quick pointers to useful resources has been invaluable. I have also gotten involved in longer discussions. Some of those, particularly those related to design and interpretation of newly published studies (especially randomized clinical trials - RCTs), have gotten very involved and&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viewpoints on Heterogeneity of Treatment Effect and Precision Medicine</title>
      <link>/post/viewpoints-on-heterogeneity-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/viewpoints-on-heterogeneity-of/</guid>
      <description>There are two stages in the understanding and implementation of RM: In most cases one can compute the absolute benefit as a function of (known or unknown) patient baseline risk using simple math, without requiring any data, once the relative efficacy is estimated. It is only at the decision point for the patient at hand that the risk estimate is&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Statistical Modeling and Machine Learning</title>
      <link>/post/navigating-statistical-modelin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/navigating-statistical-modelin/</guid>
      <description>To extend the analogy, the guideposts identified by Frank could be illustrated as a route map if put into the format of a series of junctures (and termini). Here is an example: This allegorical cartoon is simplistic: the situation is certainly much more nuanced than this. But it is more systematic thinking than is often employed (such as, &amp;lsquo;I have lots of data, therefore&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road Map for Choosing Between Statistical Modeling and Machine Learning</title>
      <link>/post/road-map-for-choosing-between-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/road-map-for-choosing-between-/</guid>
      <description>Data analysis methods may be described by their areas of applications, but for this article I&amp;rsquo;m using definitions that are strictly&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musings on Multiple Endpoints in RCTs</title>
      <link>/post/musings-on-multiple-endpoints-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/musings-on-multiple-endpoints-/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this article is not to discuss ISCHEMIA but to discuss the general study design, endpoint selection, and analysis issues ISCHEMIA raises that apply to a multitude of trials. One of the challenges in power and sample size calculations, and knowing when to stop a study, is that there are competing&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Research Through Safer Learning from Data</title>
      <link>/post/improving-research-through-saf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/improving-research-through-saf/</guid>
      <description>The following discussion concentrates on inference, although several of the concepts, especially measurement accuracy, fully pertain to exploratory data analysis. The key elements of learning from data using statistical inference involve the following: The experimental design is all important, and is what allows interpretations to be&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Medicine Mesmerized by Machine Learning?</title>
      <link>/post/is-medicine-mesmerized-by-mach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/is-medicine-mesmerized-by-mach/</guid>
      <description>Avati et al used deep learning on the 13,654 features to achieve a validated c-index of 0.93. To the authors&amp;rsquo; credit, they constructed an unbiased calibration curve, although it used binning and is very low resolution. Like many applications of ML where few statistical principles are incorporated into the algorithm, the result is a failure to make accurate predictions on the absolute risk&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information Gain From Using Ordinal Instead of Binary Outcomes</title>
      <link>/post/information-gain-from-using-or/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/information-gain-from-using-or/</guid>
      <description>The point about the increase in power can also be made by, instead of varying the effect size, varying the effect that can be detected with a fixed power of 0.9 when the degree of granularity in Y is increased. This is all about breaking ties in Y. The more ties there are, the less statistical information is present. Why is this important in study planning? Here’s an all–too–commmon&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Don&#39;t Like Percents</title>
      <link>/post/why-i-dont-like-percents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/why-i-dont-like-percents/</guid>
      <description>I have seen clinicians confused over statements such as &amp;ldquo;the chance of a stroke is 0.5%&amp;rdquo;, interpreting this as 50%. If we say &amp;ldquo;the chance of a stroke is 0.005&amp;rdquo; such confusion is less likely. And I don&amp;rsquo;t need percent signs everywhere. Percent change has even more problems than percent. I have often witnessed confusion from statements such as &amp;ldquo;the chance of stroke increased by&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>