<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theaknowlescom on DATA SCrIbers</title>
    <link>/tags/theaknowlescom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Theaknowlescom on DATA SCrIbers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/theaknowlescom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ongoing curated list of useful resources for writing articles/theses in RMarkdown</title>
      <link>/post/ongoing-curated-list-of-useful/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ongoing-curated-list-of-useful/</guid>
      <description>A list of resources I am finding helpful for preparing to write a dissertation in&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing my Twitter dashboard (i.e., finally getting to check off my more wistful to-do&#39;s)</title>
      <link>/post/implementing-my-twitter-dashbo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/implementing-my-twitter-dashbo/</guid>
      <description>When I come across a tweet containing information I would like future-me to take note of, I have a rather inelegant set of strategies for making sure it stays accessible (god forbid I merely rely on remembering; if it’s not down on an externally stored list somewhere outside my brain, it will never see the light of day again): And there it has sat for the last 6 weeks, gathering metaphorical dust in only the ways forgotten corners of the internet&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate Word Clouds in R from Conference Tweets</title>
      <link>/post/generate-word-clouds-in-r-from/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/generate-word-clouds-in-r-from/</guid>
      <description>A few considerations to bear in mind before forging ahead: Assuming there’s an agreed-upon communal hashtag for a given conference, this is a fairly quick and painless fun little task. In the case of the SAC Conference, the hashtag stays the same year to year:&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop materials</title>
      <link>/post/workshop-materials/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/workshop-materials/</guid>
      <description>The real reason that Sally and I decided not to present, instead seeking out other women in the community to do so, was that we simply knew these women were out there and wanted them to join our group. We were hopeful that, with just the right amount of pleading balanced with what we perceived to be the obvious inherent value of what we were offering, the R-savvy women in our lives (or soon to be in our lives) would agree to&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection</title>
      <link>/post/reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/reflection/</guid>
      <description>Sort of. It rolled just a wee bit and then it stopped. I’d say we’ve had a pretty stellar year. Thank you to each of you who have come out to the events, who have stuck around and headed to Milo’s with us after, and have provided input, insight, and encouragement. We are stoked to forge forward with you&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>