<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Geekologiecom on {data-scribers}</title>
    <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/tags/geekologiecom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Geekologiecom on {data-scribers}</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/tags/geekologiecom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;RIP&#39;, A Trippy Skeletal Animation For Halloween</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/rip-a-trippy-skeletal-animatio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/rip-a-trippy-skeletal-animatio/</guid>
      <description>This is &amp;lsquo;RIP&amp;rsquo;, a trippy animation created by Cyriak Harris in the spirit of Halloween that features a bunch of skeletons dancing around and getting all freaky deaky. SO MANY SKULLS. Did you count all the skulls? I counted all the skulls. &amp;ldquo;How many were there?&amp;rdquo; Too many to count. The video is pretty weird, but I like it, which is similar to how I feel about you. &amp;ldquo;But I&amp;rsquo;m not weird&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adorably Creepy Little Girl Carrying Her Own Head On A Plate Halloween Costume</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/adorably-creepy-little-girl-ca/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/adorably-creepy-little-girl-ca/</guid>
      <description>Well folks, today&amp;rsquo;s the day &amp;ndash; All Hallows&amp;rsquo; Eve. I&amp;rsquo;ve got my Ninja Turtle costume on here at work and I&amp;rsquo;ve already been asked twice if I&amp;rsquo;m an iguana because my coworkers are idiots&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alladin&#39;s Genie</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/alladins-genie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/alladins-genie/</guid>
      <description>These are several shots and videos of one-legged Paralympian skier Josh Sundquist&amp;rsquo;s 2018 Halloween costume &amp;ndash; the Genie of the Lamp from Alladin (previously: some of his past Halloween costumes). If I were a judge, I would definitely award him a perfect 10&amp;frasl;10&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jealous</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/jealous/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/jealous/</guid>
      <description>This is a video demonstration of the bicycle-based Star Destroyer costume father Andrew Guy built for his son Aidan. He says it took several months of planning and construction to have ready for Halloween, and includes a hidden speaker that blasts &amp;lsquo;The Imperial March&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Man Trying To Wheelbarrow Horse Manure Up Ramp Goes How You&#39;d Expect</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/man-trying-to-wheelbarrow-hors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/man-trying-to-wheelbarrow-hors/</guid>
      <description>When you watch a video of a man pushing a wheelbarrow of horse manure up a ramp into the back of a truck, you know one of two things is going to happen, either 1) he&amp;rsquo;s going to get shit on him, or 2) the video isn&amp;rsquo;t going to be worth&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photo Of A Black Cat That Looks Like A Crow</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/photo-of-a-black-cat-that-look/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/photo-of-a-black-cat-that-look/</guid>
      <description>This is a photo of a black cat that, because of the way its head is turned, looks like a crow&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Products That Exist</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/real-products-that-exist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/real-products-that-exist/</guid>
      <description>Because booze is precious, this is the Whiskey Vault&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/cool/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/cool/</guid>
      <description>This is a video of the Surf Lakes wavepool built in Yeppoon in Queensland, Australia&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Couple Performs A Doctor Who Themed Tango To The Show&#39;s Theme Song On BBC&#39;s Equivalent Of &#39;Dancing With The Stars&#39;</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/couple-performs-a-doctor-who-t/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/couple-performs-a-doctor-who-t/</guid>
      <description>This is a video of journalist Stacey Dooley and professional dancer Kevin Clifton performing a Doctor Who themed tango to the show&amp;rsquo;s theme song on the BBC&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Strictly Come Dancing&amp;rsquo;. Obviously, Stacey is portraying the new Thirteenth Doctor, and Kevin, Mr. Freeze. &amp;ldquo;He&amp;rsquo;s a Cyberman.&amp;rdquo; Oh &amp;ndash; right. You have to admit, it is nice to see Mr&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everybody Needs A Hobby</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/everybody-needs-a-hobby/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/everybody-needs-a-hobby/</guid>
      <description>Because it&amp;rsquo;s best to remain active during the Ultimate Frisbee offseason, this is a short video of members of the Flight Crew jump rope team demonstrating a couple of the tricks they&amp;rsquo;ve been working on recently. Pretty impressive. Obviously, I&amp;rsquo;d be a huge asset to their team. &amp;ldquo;You want to jump?&amp;rdquo; No, I want to COACH&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fascinating</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/fascinating/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/fascinating/</guid>
      <description>This is a timelapse video of two houseplants (Oxalis triangularis, aka false shamrock, and a Marantra species) seen moving throughout the day. So dynamic! It&amp;rsquo;s almost like they&amp;rsquo;re alive. &amp;ldquo;Plants are alive.&amp;rdquo; Well most of mine aren&amp;rsquo;t. And the ones that are seem so lazy. They just sit around all day drinking up all the water I should be drinking but don&amp;rsquo;t because I hate drinking water&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marine Pilot Under Investigation For Flying Invisible Wiener Pattern In Sky</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/marine-pilot-under-investigati/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/marine-pilot-under-investigati/</guid>
      <description>A US Marine pilot is currently under investigation after flying in a pattern above the Salton Sea in California&amp;rsquo;s Imperial and Coachella Valleys that very clearly resembles a penis. Just not a very big one, at least by my standards&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notoriously Difficult &#39;Flight Of The Bumblebee&#39; Performed On Bass Guitar</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/notoriously-difficult-flight-o/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/notoriously-difficult-flight-o/</guid>
      <description>Presumably to raise awareness to the plight of dying bees everywhere, this is a video of musician and Youtuber Davie504 (previously) performing Nikolai Rimsky-Korsakov&amp;rsquo;s notoriously difficult &amp;lsquo;Flight Of The Bumblebee&amp;rsquo; on bass&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Solving</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/problem-solving/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/problem-solving/</guid>
      <description>This is a video news report highlighting New South Wales Australian man Shane Swanscott, who was recently pulled over by police towing his new boat with a mobility scooter because &amp;ldquo;he needed to go fishing&amp;rdquo; after losing his license. I wonder how he lost his license in the first place. I mean, clearly he&amp;rsquo;s an exemplary decision maker&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whatever Works</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/whatever-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/whatever-works/</guid>
      <description>This is a video from Cariacica, Brazil of bus drivers in training learning what it feels like to be a tiny piece of meat pedaling down the street when a 15-ton bus comes screaming by only 1.5-meters (5-feet) away. The purpose is to teach the drivers to maintain a minimum 1.5-meters between their buses and cyclists&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deepfake Video Of Nic Cage Replacing Other Actors&#39; Faces In Iconic Movie Scenes</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/deepfake-video-of-nic-cage-rep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/deepfake-video-of-nic-cage-rep/</guid>
      <description>In even more beautiful than butterflies news, this is the latest video from Derpfakes (previously) featuring Nicolas Cage&amp;rsquo;s face replacing those of famous actors in iconic movie scenes (just like I said in the title &amp;ndash; no bait-and-switch&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fascinating</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/fascinating/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/fascinating/</guid>
      <description>This is an animated video created by Jared Owen detailing the inner workings of the humble gumball machine. I thought the engineering of the coin mechanism was particularly clever&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fictional Fight Commentary For A Battle Between Jason And Freddy</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/fictional-fight-commentary-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/fictional-fight-commentary-for/</guid>
      <description>This is a very well produced video of some fictional fight commentary for a deathmatch style battle between Jason Voorhees and Freddy Krueger. It&amp;rsquo;s twelve minutes long. It could have been five. Or less&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freaky Deaky</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/freaky-deaky/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/freaky-deaky/</guid>
      <description>This is a video from a forest in Sacré-Coeur, Quebec, Canada of high winds causing the forest floor to &amp;lsquo;breathe&amp;rsquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s actually a result of the trees&amp;rsquo; interconnected root systems being pulled upwards as the trees are yanked around by the wind&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get It!</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/get-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/get-it/</guid>
      <description>In a video that would undoubtedly make young Zombie Jonathan squeal with delight, this is some footage from the Oregon Zoo of a large African spurred tortoise named Dozer breaking into and eating a pumpkin. Just look at him go. Reminds me of myself the first time I tried to carve a pumpkin without a knife because my mom said I wasn&amp;rsquo;t ready for one yet&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Was Meant To Be</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/it-was-meant-to-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/it-was-meant-to-be/</guid>
      <description>This is a video from Istanbul, Turkey of a cat appropriately crashing the catwalk at the recent Esmod International Fashion Show in order to lick its privates, playfully bat at the models walking by, and eventually strut down the runway itself. It honestly couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more perfect&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LEGO Pop-Up Storybook Makes It To Production</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/lego-popup-storybook-makes-it-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/lego-popup-storybook-makes-it-/</guid>
      <description>These are the official product shots of the $70 &amp;lsquo;Once Upon A Brick&amp;rsquo; pop-up LEGO storybook being released November 1st&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video Of A Beautiful Butterfly Swarm In Vietnam</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/video-of-a-beautiful-butterfly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/video-of-a-beautiful-butterfly/</guid>
      <description>Because the world isn&amp;rsquo;t complete garbage yet, this is a beautiful video of hundreds of butterflies swarming in Ninh Binh, Vietnam, presumably because the person filming disturbed them. It looks like a scene out of a movie. A movie my girlfriend insist I watch with her instead of playing Red Dead Redemption 2 all weekend&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Fahrenheit 451&#39; That Can Only Be Read When Heat Is Applied Is Now Available For Preorder</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/fahrenheit-451-that-can-only-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/fahrenheit-451-that-can-only-b/</guid>
      <description>A special edition of Fahrenheit 451 is now available for preorder (previously seen HERE when it was first conceived because, like an elephant or a vindictive girlfriend, I never forget) that can only be read when heat is applied to the pages via lighter or match&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Ghostbusters Ghost Trap Automatic Cat Feeder</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/a-ghostbusters-ghost-trap-auto/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/a-ghostbusters-ghost-trap-auto/</guid>
      <description>This is the prototype Ghostbusters ghost trap automatic cat feeder created by If industries. It can operate as a computer controlled timed cat feeder or a Wi-Fi enabled device that can be triggered to open at anytime from anywhere via sms, tweet, email, or a phone call&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad Ideas</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/bad-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/bad-ideas/</guid>
      <description>This is a video of a couple intrepid explorers maniacs with a jet boat blasting their craft across the rocky flats connecting two bodies of water. I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine the boat&amp;rsquo;s hull was thrilled about that. The person filming was though &amp;ndash; I can recognize a heartfelt &amp;lsquo;Woohoo!&amp;rsquo; when I hear one&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dumbo Octopus Puts On A Show For Unmanned Submersible</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/dumbo-octopus-puts-on-a-show-f/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/dumbo-octopus-puts-on-a-show-f/</guid>
      <description>This is a video of a &amp;lsquo;big eared&amp;rsquo; (actually the animal&amp;rsquo;s mantle fins) Dumbo octopus putting on a show for the unmanned submersible Hercules near the Davidson Seamount in the Monterey Bay National Marine Sanctuary off the coast of central California. This particular specimen is about two feet long and a CERTIFIED CUTIE&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giant Industrial Pipe Spool Rolls Down Highway As Drivers Move To Avoid It</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/giant-industrial-pipe-spool-ro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/giant-industrial-pipe-spool-ro/</guid>
      <description>Seen here looking exactly like one of the daydream fantasies I have while commuting to work on a Monday morning, this is a video from Interstate 10 near Houston of a giant industrial spool rollings its way down the highway as drivers move to avoid&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Just A Scratch</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/its-just-a-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/its-just-a-scratch/</guid>
      <description>This is a very short video of a man in China driving what can only be described as a mint condition Nissan on his way to the body shop, presumably just for a detailing. You think it got flattened by a runaway industrial pipe spool? Admittedly, I&amp;rsquo;m impressed it&amp;rsquo;s still drivable&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nailed It</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/nailed-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/nailed-it/</guid>
      <description>This is the AT-AT costume custom built for a 2,000-pound Clydesdale horse by prop maker Mike&amp;rsquo;s Tiny Shop of Martinsville, Indiana in an attempt to set the Guinness World Record for largest equine Star Wars costume. Dare to dream&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>They&#39;re Coming</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/theyre-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/theyre-coming/</guid>
      <description>This is a video of two of the FlyCroTug drones developed by researchers at Stanford University and the Ecole Polytechnique Federale de Lausanne in Switzerland that are capable of working together to manipulate heavy&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Company Now Take Preorders On This $150,000 Hoverbike</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/company-now-take-preorders-on-/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/company-now-take-preorders-on-/</guid>
      <description>Hoversurf has announced it is now taking preorders on its $150,000 Hoverbike Scorpion 3 (previously seen HERE and HERE), with deliveries expected in two to six&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dad Builds Father-Daughter Mech Warrior Costume For The Two Of Them</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/dad-builds-fatherdaughter-mech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/dad-builds-fatherdaughter-mech/</guid>
      <description>This is a video demonstration of the Stalker J-1 Mech Warrior costume built by father Griddlock Cosplay for he and his daughter to wear to the Edmonton Comic Expo 2018&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explosive Experimentation</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/explosive-experimentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/explosive-experimentation/</guid>
      <description>Note: Some appropriate cursing at the very end. This is a video of two idiots men after my own heart igniting a leaf pile after dousing it with a healthy amount of gasoline. You can tell they&amp;rsquo;re seasoned professionals because of the rolled up paper towels they&amp;rsquo;re using to try to start the fire&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Flying Jack!</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/im-flying-jack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/im-flying-jack/</guid>
      <description>This is an older video of a group of kids pushing a 300kg (~660-pound) tractor tire down a hill to watch it bounce and catch some serious air before cannonballing into the lake below to start a new freshwater reef. &amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s no such thing.&amp;rdquo; There is a such thing, that&amp;rsquo;s just not what this tire is going to do&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Thinking</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/smart-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/smart-thinking/</guid>
      <description>This is a video of the San Bernardino Police Department of California using a bag of loose Doritos to lure an escaped pig named Smalls back home. In their own words while I get my arm stuck in the vending machine again&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swiss Space-Saving Toilet Bowl Doubles As A Sink</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/swiss-spacesaving-toilet-bowl-/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/swiss-spacesaving-toilet-bowl-/</guid>
      <description>This is a video demonstration of a space-saving public toilet in Switzerland (it&amp;rsquo;s a very small country) that also doubles as the bathroom&amp;rsquo;s sink. I especially like how putting the seat down with the sink running makes it look like somebody peed all over on the seat&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T-Pain&#39;s Custom Pickle Rick Wrap On His Nissan 240SX</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/tpains-custom-pickle-rick-wrap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/tpains-custom-pickle-rick-wrap/</guid>
      <description>This is an Instagram video of T-Pain unveiling and dancing in front of the custom Pickle Rick wrap he just got on his Nissan 240SX. As far as Pickle Rick car wraps go, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely the best one I&amp;rsquo;ve seen. Of course it&amp;rsquo;s also the only one I&amp;rsquo;ve seen. Kinda like how my brother is my favorite brother. &amp;ldquo;Because he&amp;rsquo;s your only brother&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apollo 11&#39;s Journey To The Moon, Annotated</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/apollo-11s-journey-to-the-moon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/apollo-11s-journey-to-the-moon/</guid>
      <description>This is a fascinating five minute video discussing the Apollo 11 mission to the moon, and what it took to be a success. SPOILER: A whole bunch of luck and magic. &amp;ldquo;It was math and science.&amp;rdquo; You know, there really is no difference if you look closely enough. See what I&amp;rsquo;m doing here? &amp;ldquo;Staring at your nipple through a magnifying glass?&amp;rdquo; I rest my case&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classic</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/classic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/classic/</guid>
      <description>FULL DISCLOSURE: I&amp;rsquo;ve been puking for three days and operating with almost no sleep or food in my system but I&amp;rsquo;m gonna try the best I can but I really don&amp;rsquo;t feel well. NASA was recently able to repair a gyroscope that was spinning too fast aboard the Hubble Space Telescope and preventing the telescope from being able to lock onto a target by turning it off and back on again&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Halloween Light Show Choreographed To The Best Of Michael Jackson</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/home-halloween-light-show-chor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/home-halloween-light-show-chor/</guid>
      <description>Because everyone has that one neighbor, this is an over-the-top Halloween home light show set to some of Michael Jackson&amp;rsquo;s biggest hits. I already didn&amp;rsquo;t feel good when I started watching it, and it definitely wasn&amp;rsquo;t the medicine for my sickness. All those blinking lights &amp;ndash; I think they may have altered my brain chemistry. Ask me something&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lunatic Parkours Down Side Of Parking Garage</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/lunatic-parkours-down-side-of-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/lunatic-parkours-down-side-of-/</guid>
      <description>Aim for an SUV. Because stairs and elevators are for fans of living, this is a video of some maniac parkouring down the exterior of a parking garage. Personally, I would have driven my car through the wall, but that&amp;rsquo;s just me and everything I learned about driving I learned from The Dukes Of Hazzard and Fast And Furious movies. Let&amp;rsquo;s launch over it&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks, Internet!</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/thanks-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/thanks-internet/</guid>
      <description>This is a video of a &amp;lsquo;Sale&amp;rsquo; crazy dancing inflatable tube man shaking all his cylindrical parts to AWOLNATION&amp;rsquo;S &amp;lsquo;Sail&amp;rsquo;. Apparently the person filming had to make two u-turns to capture this video, although I&amp;rsquo;d be willing to drive over a median and crash off a bridge into a river for footage so perfect&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timelapse Of A Glacier Flowing Through A Valley Like A River</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/timelapse-of-a-glacier-flowing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/timelapse-of-a-glacier-flowing/</guid>
      <description>This is a video from BBC Earth Lab discussing the flowing movement of glaciers. Scientists have calculated the particular glacier in this timelapse moves about 275 meters per year, or about three-quarters the length of your penis. Now print this article out and show you friends and never say I haven&amp;rsquo;t done anything nice for you&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dead, Back Tomorrow</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/dead-back-tomorrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/dead-back-tomorrow/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s up, I am dead with the sickness no thanks to my girlfriend, she is trying to kill me and I probably deserve it&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Flattened World Map Showing All Countries To Proper Scale</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/a-flattened-world-map-showing-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/a-flattened-world-map-showing-/</guid>
      <description>Note: Larger version HERE. Tired of the traditional global mapping method (the Mercator projection, which makes landmasses near the poles appear larger than they really are) this is a map created by Redditor neilrkaye that shows all the countries to proper scale. I learned a lot by looking at it&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>China Plans To Put Luminous Artificial Moon In Orbit To Light Streets At Night</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/china-plans-to-put-luminous-ar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/china-plans-to-put-luminous-ar/</guid>
      <description>China intends to launch a luminous artificial satellite into geosynchronous orbit above Chengdu (the capital of China&amp;rsquo;s southwestern Sichuan province) by 2020, to help supplement street lights at night and save as much as $173-million on electricity annually. THE FUTURE&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fallout 76 Green-Glowing Vault Boy LED Lamp</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/fallout-76-greenglowing-vault-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/fallout-76-greenglowing-vault-/</guid>
      <description>This is the $40 Official Fallout 76 Vault Boy LED Lamp available for preorder from Geekstore. The lamp is USB powered and shines green like a ghoul &amp;lsquo;Glowing One&amp;rsquo; from the franchise&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressive!</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/impressive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/impressive/</guid>
      <description>Hot on the heels of the Predator costume she crocheted for her older son, this is the Slimer costume Crochetverse freehand crocheted (no pattern) for her youngest son. Plus she brushed the finished product with some luminescent paint SO IT GLOWS IN THE DARK. How cool is that? &amp;ldquo;Very cool&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spider On Police Dashcam Appear As A Giant Spider Crawling Across Street Towards Officer</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/spider-on-police-dashcam-appea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/spider-on-police-dashcam-appea/</guid>
      <description>This is a short video from the dashcam of a Fulshear, Texas police officer of a spider that, thanks to its proximity the camera, creates an optical illusion that it&amp;rsquo;s actually a giant spider crawling across the street towards the&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Art&#39;</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/art/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/art/</guid>
      <description>This is a video of Belgian Youtuber PressTube pouring molten aluminum into an underground wasp&amp;rsquo;s nest to create a relatively unimpressive 24-pound casting of its shape (previously: a guy who did the same thing with ant hills and made a lot of ants dead and people angry in the&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deepfake AI Face-Swapping Technology Replaces Alden Ehrenreich&#39;s Face With Young Harrison Ford&#39;s In Solo</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/deepfake-ai-faceswapping-techn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/deepfake-ai-faceswapping-techn/</guid>
      <description>This is a video created by Youtuber derpfakes using deepfake artificial intelligence face-swapping technology to replace Alden Ehrenreich&amp;rsquo;s face with the face of a pre-1977 Harrison Ford in some scenes from Solo: A Star Wars Story&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feeding Time</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/feeding-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/feeding-time/</guid>
      <description>This is some security camera footage from a mall in China of a woman running across a gangway and falling into an open lemon shark tank during feeding time. The gangway is supposed to be off-limits during feedings, but the woman, who was running to make a meeting on time, either didn&amp;rsquo;t see or ignored the signage&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Those Superpowers Early</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/getting-those-superpowers-earl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/getting-those-superpowers-earl/</guid>
      <description>This is a video from the Xiaolan Railway Station in South China of a young boy who rides through the x-ray baggage scanner when his father isn&amp;rsquo;t paying attention (previously: a woman who rode through an x-ray scanner to make sure her purse wasn&amp;rsquo;t stolen)&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guy Sinks Full-Scale Jason Voorhees In Lake To Scare Other Divers</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/guy-sinks-fullscale-jason-voor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/guy-sinks-fullscale-jason-voor/</guid>
      <description>These are a couple videos of the Jason Voorhees effigy that diver Curtis Lahr sunk in a lake that&amp;rsquo;s popular for diving near Crosby, Minnesota&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weather Channel Demonstrates Its Immersive Wildfire Visualizations</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/the-weather-channel-demonstrat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/the-weather-channel-demonstrat/</guid>
      <description>Seen here really feeling the heat, this a video of a Weather Channel reporter demonstrating the company&amp;rsquo;s new immersive visualization technology (previously seen in its Hurricane Florence coverage) in a California wildfires segment. I liked how some of the flames and debris pass in front of the reporter. Really makes you feel like you&amp;rsquo;re right there, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it? &amp;ldquo;Not really&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wide Turns</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/wide-turns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/wide-turns/</guid>
      <description>Note: Some language. This is a video from Midland, Texas of a truck driver attempting to make a right turn and trying to run over a utility pole and knock down some power lines in the process. Turns: I&amp;rsquo;ll be the first to admit that making them can be tricky. &amp;ldquo;We don&amp;rsquo;t even have a mailbox anymore&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Horror Movie Character Garden Gnomes</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/custom-horror-movie-character-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/custom-horror-movie-character-/</guid>
      <description>These are some of the custom horror movie character garden gnomes (&amp;lsquo;Garden Nightmares&amp;rsquo;) made and sold by Casper and Sadie Revenant of RevenantFX (also available in their Etsy shop). They cost around $55 apiece and make the perfect addition to your Halloween garden or pumpkin patch&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fendi Pulls $1,000 Scarf After People Say It Looks Like Lady Privates</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/fendi-pulls-1000-scarf-after-p/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/fendi-pulls-1000-scarf-after-p/</guid>
      <description>Italian luxury fashion brand Fendi has pulled its $1,000 &amp;lsquo;Touch Of Fur&amp;rsquo; shawl from online sale after everyone on the internet agreed it looks like a vagina&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Warriors Really Fought In 14th Century Armor</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/how-warriors-really-fought-in-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/how-warriors-really-fought-in-/</guid>
      <description>This is a video discussion and demonstration of how medieval warriors really fought while wearing full armor. Basically, just slashing away with a sword was a waste of energy since the sword won&amp;rsquo;t cut through plate or mail armor&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Man Spends 200 Hours Building Entirely Wooden Bike (Except For The Chain Rollers And A Few Washers)</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/man-spends-200-hours-building-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/man-spends-200-hours-building-/</guid>
      <description>This is a video of Youtuber The Q spending 200 hours building a rideable bicycle entirely out of wood. Well, except for the chain rollers (the parts of the chain that make contact with the pedal gear) and a few washers, just like I mentioned in the title. Do a bunny hop! Obviously, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely not the most practical bike in the world to ride&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks, Internet!</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/thanks-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/thanks-internet/</guid>
      <description>This is &amp;lsquo;Beat The Devil Out Of It&amp;rsquo;, a 46-minute compilation that allegedly includes footage of every time Bob Ross cleaned a paintbrush on The Joy Of Painting&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watch A Bridge Buckle After A Charter Bus Ignores The Bridge&#39;s 10-Ton Weight Limit</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/watch-a-bridge-buckle-after-a-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/watch-a-bridge-buckle-after-a-/</guid>
      <description>This is a video from the one-lane Beaver Bridge in Beaver, Arkansas of a charter bus ignoring the bridge&amp;rsquo;s 10-ton weight limit and crossing, despite these buses typically weighing three to four times that&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Well Hello There</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/well-hello-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/well-hello-there/</guid>
      <description>This is the 1:4 scale Dr. Ian Malcolm (Jeff Goldblum) statue created by Chronicle Collectibles and available from Sideshow Toys&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why You Don&#39;t Overfill Your Car Tires, A Public Service Announcement</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/why-you-dont-overfill-your-car/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/why-you-dont-overfill-your-car/</guid>
      <description>This is a video from Chevy Chase, Maryland, of a man who apparently kept putting air in his right front tire for over two minutes before it finally gave up trying to rationalize with him and blew up in his face, which he&amp;rsquo;s lucky to still&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Puppy Doing Cat Things&#39;</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/puppy-doing-cat-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/puppy-doing-cat-things/</guid>
      <description>Presumably after learning a thing or two from his feline friends on the back of the school bus, this is a video of a puppy knocking a line of shampoo and soap bottles into the shower one-by-one. He looks pretty proud of himself, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it? He also looks like he has an adult dog head on a puppy body&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boston Dynamics&#39; Spot Robot Dances To &#39;Uptown Funk&#39;</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/boston-dynamics-spot-robot-dan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/boston-dynamics-spot-robot-dan/</guid>
      <description>Because not perceiving a threat as a threat is how they&amp;rsquo;re gonna get us, this is a video of Boston Dynamics&amp;rsquo; Spot quadruped robot dancing to Bruno Mars&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;Uptown Funk&amp;rsquo;. Now I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what that move it&amp;rsquo;s performing in the gif is called besides inappropriate&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally, A Super Mario Boo Ghost Beanbag Chair</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/finally-a-super-mario-boo-ghos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/finally-a-super-mario-boo-ghos/</guid>
      <description>This is the officially licensed Super Mario Bros Boo beanbag chair available from ThinkGeek and Gamestop. It costs around $140 (plus shipping or pickup from a Gamestop) and measures approximately 38&amp;rdquo; wide x 28&amp;rdquo; tall x 38&amp;rdquo; deep&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Developer Developing Snetris, A Snake &#43; Tetris Mashup</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/game-developer-developing-snet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/game-developer-developing-snet/</guid>
      <description>This is a short video of Snetris, a Snake and Tetris mashup currently being developed by Portuguese crowdfunded minigame creator nyunesa&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not Today, Death!</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/not-today-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/not-today-death/</guid>
      <description>This is some dashcam footage from a mountain road in southwest China of a boulder absolutely obliterating the hood of an SUV before splintering a tree into toothpicks and continuing its way down the mountain&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh Wow</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/oh-wow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/oh-wow/</guid>
      <description>This is the Hallmark Keepsake Star Wars Death Star Lighted Christmas Tree Topper. It costs around $100, lights up blue or red with green superlaser, and can play the Imperial March and classic Star Wars theme (lights and songs selected via included remote control)&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2018 Wind Games Indoor Skydiving Freestyle Championship Performance</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/the-2018-wind-games-indoor-sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/the-2018-wind-games-indoor-sky/</guid>
      <description>These are two videos of 15-year old Kyra Poh&amp;rsquo;s winning indoor skydiving freestyle performance at the 2018 Wind Games in Empuriabrava, Spain. And speaking of wind games&amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m not pulling your finger.&amp;rdquo; BRRAAAAAAP! My trigger is faulty anyways&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uh-Oh</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/uhoh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/uhoh/</guid>
      <description>This is a video of Pro Mod drag racer Mike Bowman&amp;rsquo;s parachute failing during a qualifying race in St. Louis. Thankfully, there&amp;rsquo;s a safety net at the end of the track that catches his &amp;lsquo;69 Chevelle, and he&amp;rsquo;s able to walk away from the incident unharmed&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom $1,350 Game Boy, Nintendo And Super Nintendo Themed Air Jordans</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/custom-1350-game-boy-nintendo-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/custom-1350-game-boy-nintendo-/</guid>
      <description>These are the Game Boy, Nintendo and Super Nintendo themed custom Air Jordan IV&amp;rsquo;s modded by Freaker Sneaks Customs. Each design is limited to only ten pairs and costs around $1,350. That is a lot of money. The only thing you&amp;rsquo;re going to see me wearing on my feet that cost more than $1,000 are these rocket boots&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Footage Of Boston Dynamics&#39; Spot Robot Being Field-Tested At Construction Sites</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/footage-of-boston-dynamics-spo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/footage-of-boston-dynamics-spo/</guid>
      <description>This is a video from harbinger of the apocalypse Boston Dynamics field-testing their Spot robotic dog robot at construction sites. It, uh, it looks very capable. I especially like that demogorgon face move it pulls at the very end of the gif, that was nice and terrifying. &amp;ldquo;We have to stop them.&amp;rdquo; You do it, I&amp;rsquo;m tired of caring. I&amp;rsquo;ve already given up and accepted my fate&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High School Dance Team Performs Impressive Harry Potter Themed Routine</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/high-school-dance-team-perform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/high-school-dance-team-perform/</guid>
      <description>This is a video of the the Arizona based Walden Grove High School PAC Dance Team performing a Harry Potter themed routine at their homecoming pep rally. They also performed the routine during half time of their homecoming football game. That must have taken a lot of choreography&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not Today!</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/not-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/not-today/</guid>
      <description>This is a video from the Isle Of Skye in Scotland where heavy winds caused by a storm blew a waterfall on Talisker Beach back up over the cliff it was trying to fall from. That&amp;rsquo;s pretty intense&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Savannah, Georgia Seeks Person Who Attached Googly Eyes To American Revolution Statue</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/savannah-georgia-seeks-person-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/savannah-georgia-seeks-person-/</guid>
      <description>The city of Savannah, Georgia is seeking the person who adhered googly eyes to the American Revolution statue of Nathanael Greene in Johnson Square so they can potentially charge them with criminal trespassing instead of patting them on the back and sharing a LOL&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skydivers Take Turns Falling Through A Ring Of Other Skydivers Holding Hands</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/skydivers-take-turns-falling-t/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/skydivers-take-turns-falling-t/</guid>
      <description>This is a video of a bunch of skydivers holding hands to form a ring while other skydivers take turns falling through their little mile-high friendship circle. Why? I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure, but I assume they got bored of regular low-fat vanilla flavored skydiving and decided they needed to invent games to spice it up a bit&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So That&#39;s What That Sounds Like</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/so-thats-what-that-sounds-like/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/so-thats-what-that-sounds-like/</guid>
      <description>This is a short video of an extremely eyebrowed young caracal cat begging for/possibly demanding some food from its caretaker. The typically nocturnal and secretive (rarely observed in nature) caracal is native to Africa, the Middle East, Central Asia, and India, and can grow up to 40 pounds at maturity&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sorry I&#39;m Late!</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/sorry-im-late/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/sorry-im-late/</guid>
      <description>This is some security cam footage from a bank in Nanning, southern China, of a five-foot python falling out of the ceiling and disrupting a staff meeting. &amp;ldquo;Shit, this isn&amp;rsquo;t the vault!&amp;rdquo; I imagine the snake realizing as it fell. Sucks too because now I&amp;rsquo;m gonna have to start training a whole new python&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Smile Every Day</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/a-smile-every-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/a-smile-every-day/</guid>
      <description>This is the 2019 Bob Ross The Joy Of Painting wall calendar ($15). Each month features a Bob Ross painting from the show, along with an inspiring quote to keep you from throwing yourself out the picture of a window you drew and taped to the wall in your office&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bantha Milk, Trash Compactor, Wookie, Ewok, Yoda&#39;s Cooking Pot</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/bantha-milk-trash-compactor-wo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/bantha-milk-trash-compactor-wo/</guid>
      <description>These are the Star Wars Original Trilogy Limited Edition Candle Sets available from Merchoid. Each movie is represented by five different candles, all representing a smell from that particular movie. Or they might all just smell like ass, who knows&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busted!</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/busted/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/busted/</guid>
      <description>Seen here looking like a shot straight out of the telenovela Hermano Mayor, this is a screencap from Google Maps near the Bridge Of Sighs in Lima, Peru of a woman with a man&amp;rsquo;s head in her lap&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classic</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/classic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/classic/</guid>
      <description>Because what good is a maternity photoshoot if you can&amp;rsquo;t use it to pay homage to one of your favorite sci-fi horror films, this is the alien chestburster themed shoot captured by photographer Li Carter for Halloween lovers Todd and Nicole Cameron to celebrate their upcoming pregnancy&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crazy Little One-Legged Jumping Robot Demonstrates Its Precision Jumping Skills</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/crazy-little-onelegged-jumping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/crazy-little-onelegged-jumping/</guid>
      <description>Seen here looking suspiciously like the Pixar lamp has some explaining to do, this is an impressive video demonstration of the Salto-1P one-legged jumping robot developed at The University Of California Berkeley&amp;rsquo;s Biomimetic Millisystems Lab. It can hop exactly where it wants to, when it wants to&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Didn&#39;t See That Coming</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/didnt-see-that-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/didnt-see-that-coming/</guid>
      <description>Yeah, I felt like it was different in the movie&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Thinking</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/smart-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/smart-thinking/</guid>
      <description>Because doing things the right way is never as fun as doing things the completely wrong and incredibly dangerous way, this is a video of a group of men trying to knock down a short concrete wall by repeatedly backing into it with a&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>