<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Geekologiecom on {data-scribers}</title>
    <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/tags/geekologiecom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Geekologiecom on {data-scribers}</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/tags/geekologiecom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally, A Super Mario Boo Ghost Beanbag Chair</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/finally-a-super-mario-boo-ghos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/finally-a-super-mario-boo-ghos/</guid>
      <description>This is the officially licensed Super Mario Bros Boo beanbag chair available from ThinkGeek and Gamestop. It costs around $140 (plus shipping or pickup from a Gamestop) and measures approximately 38&amp;rdquo; wide x 28&amp;rdquo; tall x 38&amp;rdquo; deep&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uh-Oh</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/uhoh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/uhoh/</guid>
      <description>This is a video of Pro Mod drag racer Mike Bowman&amp;rsquo;s parachute failing during a qualifying race in St. Louis. Thankfully, there&amp;rsquo;s a safety net at the end of the track that catches his &amp;lsquo;69 Chevelle, and he&amp;rsquo;s able to walk away from the incident unharmed&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom $1,350 Game Boy, Nintendo And Super Nintendo Themed Air Jordans</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/custom-1350-game-boy-nintendo-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/custom-1350-game-boy-nintendo-/</guid>
      <description>These are the Game Boy, Nintendo and Super Nintendo themed custom Air Jordan IV&amp;rsquo;s modded by Freaker Sneaks Customs. Each design is limited to only ten pairs and costs around $1,350. That is a lot of money. The only thing you&amp;rsquo;re going to see me wearing on my feet that cost more than $1,000 are these rocket boots&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Footage Of Boston Dynamics&#39; Spot Robot Being Field-Tested At Construction Sites</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/footage-of-boston-dynamics-spo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/footage-of-boston-dynamics-spo/</guid>
      <description>This is a video from harbinger of the apocalypse Boston Dynamics field-testing their Spot robotic dog robot at construction sites. It, uh, it looks very capable. I especially like that demogorgon face move it pulls at the very end of the gif, that was nice and terrifying. &amp;ldquo;We have to stop them.&amp;rdquo; You do it, I&amp;rsquo;m tired of caring. I&amp;rsquo;ve already given up and accepted my fate&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High School Dance Team Performs Impressive Harry Potter Themed Routine</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/high-school-dance-team-perform/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/high-school-dance-team-perform/</guid>
      <description>This is a video of the the Arizona based Walden Grove High School PAC Dance Team performing a Harry Potter themed routine at their homecoming pep rally. They also performed the routine during half time of their homecoming football game. That must have taken a lot of choreography&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not Today!</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/not-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/not-today/</guid>
      <description>This is a video from the Isle Of Skye in Scotland where heavy winds caused by a storm blew a waterfall on Talisker Beach back up over the cliff it was trying to fall from. That&amp;rsquo;s pretty intense&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Savannah, Georgia Seeks Person Who Attached Googly Eyes To American Revolution Statue</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/savannah-georgia-seeks-person-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/savannah-georgia-seeks-person-/</guid>
      <description>The city of Savannah, Georgia is seeking the person who adhered googly eyes to the American Revolution statue of Nathanael Greene in Johnson Square so they can potentially charge them with criminal trespassing instead of patting them on the back and sharing a LOL&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skydivers Take Turns Falling Through A Ring Of Other Skydivers Holding Hands</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/skydivers-take-turns-falling-t/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/skydivers-take-turns-falling-t/</guid>
      <description>This is a video of a bunch of skydivers holding hands to form a ring while other skydivers take turns falling through their little mile-high friendship circle. Why? I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure, but I assume they got bored of regular low-fat vanilla flavored skydiving and decided they needed to invent games to spice it up a bit&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So That&#39;s What That Sounds Like</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/so-thats-what-that-sounds-like/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/so-thats-what-that-sounds-like/</guid>
      <description>This is a short video of an extremely eyebrowed young caracal cat begging for/possibly demanding some food from its caretaker. The typically nocturnal and secretive (rarely observed in nature) caracal is native to Africa, the Middle East, Central Asia, and India, and can grow up to 40 pounds at maturity&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sorry I&#39;m Late!</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/sorry-im-late/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/sorry-im-late/</guid>
      <description>This is some security cam footage from a bank in Nanning, southern China, of a five-foot python falling out of the ceiling and disrupting a staff meeting. &amp;ldquo;Shit, this isn&amp;rsquo;t the vault!&amp;rdquo; I imagine the snake realizing as it fell. Sucks too because now I&amp;rsquo;m gonna have to start training a whole new python&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Smile Every Day</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/a-smile-every-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/a-smile-every-day/</guid>
      <description>This is the 2019 Bob Ross The Joy Of Painting wall calendar ($15). Each month features a Bob Ross painting from the show, along with an inspiring quote to keep you from throwing yourself out the picture of a window you drew and taped to the wall in your office&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bantha Milk, Trash Compactor, Wookie, Ewok, Yoda&#39;s Cooking Pot</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/bantha-milk-trash-compactor-wo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/bantha-milk-trash-compactor-wo/</guid>
      <description>These are the Star Wars Original Trilogy Limited Edition Candle Sets available from Merchoid. Each movie is represented by five different candles, all representing a smell from that particular movie. Or they might all just smell like ass, who knows&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busted!</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/busted/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/busted/</guid>
      <description>Seen here looking like a shot straight out of the telenovela Hermano Mayor, this is a screencap from Google Maps near the Bridge Of Sighs in Lima, Peru of a woman with a man&amp;rsquo;s head in her lap&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classic</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/classic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/classic/</guid>
      <description>Because what good is a maternity photoshoot if you can&amp;rsquo;t use it to pay homage to one of your favorite sci-fi horror films, this is the alien chestburster themed shoot captured by photographer Li Carter for Halloween lovers Todd and Nicole Cameron to celebrate their upcoming pregnancy&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crazy Little One-Legged Jumping Robot Demonstrates Its Precision Jumping Skills</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/crazy-little-onelegged-jumping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/crazy-little-onelegged-jumping/</guid>
      <description>Seen here looking suspiciously like the Pixar lamp has some explaining to do, this is an impressive video demonstration of the Salto-1P one-legged jumping robot developed at The University Of California Berkeley&amp;rsquo;s Biomimetic Millisystems Lab. It can hop exactly where it wants to, when it wants to&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Didn&#39;t See That Coming</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/didnt-see-that-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/didnt-see-that-coming/</guid>
      <description>Yeah, I felt like it was different in the movie&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Thinking</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/smart-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/smart-thinking/</guid>
      <description>Because doing things the right way is never as fun as doing things the completely wrong and incredibly dangerous way, this is a video of a group of men trying to knock down a short concrete wall by repeatedly backing into it with a&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>