<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wenlongliugithubio on {&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;data sc&lt;/span&gt;r&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;bers}</title>
    <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/tags/wenlongliugithubio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wenlongliugithubio on {&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;data sc&lt;/span&gt;r&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;bers}</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/tags/wenlongliugithubio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate animated tracking maps for hurricanes and typhoons</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/generate-animated-tracking-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/generate-animated-tracking-map/</guid>
      <description>Further data cleaning is needed to reformat the datetime and rename a column. We can also save the animation into gif files, instead of embedding the animation. R and related packages are able to conveniently draw both static and animated maps for tracking hurricanes or typhoons. Further analysis, such as real-time tracking of hurricanes, will be conducted in the&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate a reproducible map for county-level fertilizer estimation data in U.S.A. using R</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/generate-a-reproducible-map-fo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/generate-a-reproducible-map-fo/</guid>
      <description>More than 70% of researchers have tried and failed to reproduce another scientist’s experiments, and more than half have failed to reproduce their own experiments. There are also some packages required to reproduce this post. If you have not installed them, please run the following codes. After installing all the libraries, we should include them in the R session to run the following&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brief introduction of storm hysteresis effects in solute concentration-stream discharge (C-Q) relationship</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/brief-introduction-of-storm-hy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/brief-introduction-of-storm-hy/</guid>
      <description>Generally, in order to investigate the dynamics of stream discharge and solute concentrations (C-Q relationship) in a watershed, researchers and environmental engineers usually set up monitoring stations in the watershed&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hellow world!</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/hellow-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/hellow-world/</guid>
      <description>I build this website to achieve two goals: helping others know more about my professional achievements, and presenting my most latest output (with details) to persons of interest. Therefore, I will list my publications, including journal articles, conference presentations and proceedings, and book chapters (if any)&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>