<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wenlongliugithubio on rscribers</title>
    <link>/tags/wenlongliugithubio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wenlongliugithubio on rscribers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/wenlongliugithubio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate animated tracking maps for hurricanes and typhoons</title>
      <link>/post/generate-animated-tracking-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/generate-animated-tracking-map/</guid>
      <description>As of now, Sep. 11th, 2018, Hurricane Florence (Category 4) is approaching to eastern coastal areas of United States. There are many ways to track the path of hurricanes (or typhoons) to conduct further analysis, such as flash flooding, ocean surge and property damages. In this blog, the author tries to plot the tracking of hurricanes, using both stastic and animated maps, with the help of R and related packages. Specifically, this blog is a reproducible&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate a reproducible map for county-level fertilizer estimation data in U.S.A. using R</title>
      <link>/post/generate-a-reproducible-map-fo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/generate-a-reproducible-map-fo/</guid>
      <description>Introduction and motivation Nutrient input to agricultural watersheds is a very popular topic among researchers, engineers and stakeholders. Researchers in United State Geographic Services (USGS) spent a considerable amount of time and efforts to generate fertilizr estimation dataset from synthetic fertilizer and&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights from intensive water quality sampling in a drained agriculutral field</title>
      <link>/post/insights-from-intensive-water-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/insights-from-intensive-water-/</guid>
      <description>Preferred citation: Liu, W , B Maxwell, F Birgand, M Youssef, GM Chescheir. “Insights from intensive water quality sampling in a drained agriculutral field” Agricultural Drainage Management Systems Task Force/NCERA 217, Raleigh, April 11-12,&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-term temporal variation of nitrate concentration-stream discharge (C-Q) relationship for an agrcultural watershed in Midwest USA</title>
      <link>/post/longterm-temporal-variation-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/longterm-temporal-variation-of/</guid>
      <description>Preferred citation: Liu, W , S Tian, M Youssef, F Birgand, GM Chescheir. “Long-term temporal variation of nitrate concentration-stream discharge (C-Q) relationship for an agrcultural watershed in Midwest USA” Agricultural Drainage Management Systems Task Force/NCERA 217, Raleigh, April 11-12,&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brief introduction of storm hysteresis effects in solute concentration-stream discharge (C-Q) relationship</title>
      <link>/post/brief-introduction-of-storm-hy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/brief-introduction-of-storm-hy/</guid>
      <description>What are storm hysteresis effects? Generally, in order to investigate the dynamics of stream discharge and solute concentrations (C-Q relationship) in a watershed, researchers and environmental engineers usually set up monitoring stations in the watershed&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High frequency measurements in a drained agricultural field</title>
      <link>/post/high-frequency-measurements-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/high-frequency-measurements-in/</guid>
      <description>In order to further investigate the water movement and nutrient transport from agricultural fields, we developed equipment and algorithms to zoom in the hydrograph and chemograph both spatially and&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transforming denitrifying bioreactors research and application</title>
      <link>/post/transforming-denitrifying-bior/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/transforming-denitrifying-bior/</guid>
      <description>Preferred citation: Birgand, F, B Maxwell, S Tian, W Liu , L Negm, M Youssef, G Chescheir, L Schipper, L Christianson, M Helmers, D Williams. &amp;ldquo;Transforming denitrifying bioreactors research and application: unveiling the inside of the blackbox&amp;rdquo; USDA NIFA and NSF Water and Soils Meeting, Project Director Meeting, Jan. 29-31,&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hellow world!</title>
      <link>/post/hellow-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hellow-world/</guid>
      <description>Since Jan. 2018, my brand new website is published online. The website is powered by Blogdown and Hugo-academic , and deployed by Github Pages . All the codes are open to public and available at my github repository . I build this website to achieve two goals: helping others know more about my professional achievements, and presenting my most latest output (with details) to persons of&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nitrate concentration-drainage flow (C-Q) relationship for a drained agricultural field in Eastern North Carolina Plain</title>
      <link>/post/nitrate-concentrationdrainage-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/nitrate-concentrationdrainage-/</guid>
      <description>Preferred citation: Liu, W , M Youssef, F Birgand, GM Chescheir, B Maxwell, S Tian. “Nitrate concentration-drainage flow (C-Q) relationship for a drained agricultural field in Eastern North Carolina Plain” AGU fall meeting, New Orleans, December 11-15,&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>