<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Redbandsportsnet on {data-scribers}</title>
    <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/tags/redbandsportsnet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Redbandsportsnet on {data-scribers}</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/tags/redbandsportsnet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NBA scoring is up, and so are lopsided scores</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/nba-scoring-is-up-and-so-are-l/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/nba-scoring-is-up-and-so-are-l/</guid>
      <description>There has been lots of talk recently about the increase in scoring in the NBA this season. The reasons seems obvious: the league’s recent move towards volume three-point shooting continues, and three rules changes have resulted in more fouls, more free throws and more possessions per game&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The price of chicken wings in Philadelphia</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/the-price-of-chicken-wings-in-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/the-price-of-chicken-wings-in-/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago, a Twitter user posted a photo of a restaurant menu page with an alarming array of choices&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reviewing the 2018 MLB projections for wins and home runs</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/reviewing-the-2018-mlb-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/reviewing-the-2018-mlb-project/</guid>
      <description>Back in March we investigated some 2018 season predictions from sports books and statistical projections published at FanGraphs.com. Here are the initial projections for home runs. The players shown are those offered for over-under betting by Westgate Sports Book in Las Vegas&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The new Murderers&#39; Row</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/the-new-murderers-row/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/the-new-murderers-row/</guid>
      <description>Watching a Yankees-Red Sox game at the end of the 2018 regular season, the Fox announcers mentioned that the Yankees needed just one more home run from a No. 9 hitter to have 20 home runs from every spot in the batting order. Sometimes I like to fact-check these things, mostly to see what else I can learn&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A short history of Yankees-Red Sox game lengths</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/a-short-history-of-yankeesred-/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/a-short-history-of-yankeesred-/</guid>
      <description>When the Red Sox and Yankees met in the 2018 American League Division Series, the subject of their extreme game lengths came up&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toronto municipal election 2018</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/toronto-municipal-election-201/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/toronto-municipal-election-201/</guid>
      <description>This exercise started as something else but I’ve been playing around with different ideas around the contentious Toronto municipal election and I ended up trying to work with shapefiles in R&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A consideration of the 2018 Cy Young races</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/a-consideration-of-the-2018-cy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/a-consideration-of-the-2018-cy/</guid>
      <description>On the second-last Sunday of the season, the Rays’ Blake Snell threw at the Rogers Centre against the Blue Jays. The Blue Jays telecast was full of praise for Snell, who’s had a breakout season in 2018&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blue Jays attendance is down probably because they were bad last year</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/blue-jays-attendance-is-down-p/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/blue-jays-attendance-is-down-p/</guid>
      <description>A narrative being spun around Toronto is that Blue Jays ticket sales are weak this season because the current front office of president Mark Shapiro and general manager Ross Atkins are being too … something. It’s hard to pin down what the two executives have done wrong because the goal posts move a lot&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did the 16-team format actually ruin the Brier and Scotties?</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/did-the-16team-format-actually/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/did-the-16team-format-actually/</guid>
      <description>By Nick Faris and Guy Spurrier Brad Gushue had reason to be ruffled. It was last Wednesday in Regina, and the Team Canada skip had just suffered his first loss at the Brier, a 10-7 defeat to Brendan Bottcher of Alberta&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many home runs is Josh Donaldson predicted to hit in 2018</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/how-many-home-runs-is-josh-don/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/how-many-home-runs-is-josh-don/</guid>
      <description>Last week, Birds All Day podcast cohost Drew Fairservice re-tweeted some over-under betting lines on individual home run totals for the coming baseball season. Over on Goldy and Bryce Harper plz. https://t.co/Smha0KYulI - Drew F (@DrewGROF) February 26, 2018 In the replies to the tweet, he wondered how the lines compared to projections&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How good were the offences in the Super Bowl</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/how-good-were-the-offences-in-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/how-good-were-the-offences-in-/</guid>
      <description>Sunday’s Super Bowl set 17 statistical records and tied 12 more, according to research by the Elias Sports Bureau. The 1,151 combined total yards by the Eagles and Patriots obliterated the old record by 222 yards. Below is a histogram showing the combined total yards of the 52 Super Bowls, sorted into bins of 25 yards&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Super Bowl QBs get more babies named after them?</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/do-super-bowl-qbs-get-more-bab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/do-super-bowl-qbs-get-more-bab/</guid>
      <description>On Jan. 23, Sports Illustrated posted the following tweet, which got us thinking. Fourteen years ago, a 7-year-old in Foxboro told Tom Brady he had named his baby brother after him&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can LeBron become the greatest scorer in NBA history?</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/can-lebron-become-the-greatest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/can-lebron-become-the-greatest/</guid>
      <description>LeBron James became the seventh player in NBA history to surpass 30,000 points in his career last night when he scored 28 points in Cleveland’s 114-102 loss in San Antonio. The 30,000th points came on a long two-pointer at the end of the first quarter&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genie Bouchard and tennis Elo ratings</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/genie-bouchard-and-tennis-elo-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/genie-bouchard-and-tennis-elo-/</guid>
      <description>When the next WTA rankings come out on Jan. 29, Eugenie Bouchard will have a doubles ranking that is higher than her singles ranking. Since she rarely plays doubles, it’s a pretty stark picture of the state of her game&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian figure skating champions</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/canadian-figure-skating-champi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/canadian-figure-skating-champi/</guid>
      <description>These four plots were prepared for publication with final day coverage of the 2018 Canadian figure skating championships. There were a few troubles with the data, as seen in the code notations below&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Likelihood Jon Gruden finishes his 10-year Raiders contract</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/likelihood-jon-gruden-finishes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/likelihood-jon-gruden-finishes/</guid>
      <description>At 3 p.m. today, the Oakland Raiders will hold a press conference to introduce Jon Gruden as their next head coach&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>