<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mouseimagingcentregithubioblog on {&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;data sc&lt;/span&gt;r&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;bers}</title>
    <link>/tags/mouseimagingcentregithubioblog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mouseimagingcentregithubioblog on {&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;data sc&lt;/span&gt;r&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;bers}</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/mouseimagingcentregithubioblog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Highlights From APPNING and ISMRM 2018</title>
      <link>/post/highlights-from-appning-and-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/highlights-from-appning-and-is/</guid>
      <description>Jacob’s Highlights I recently attended the Workshop on Animal Population Imaging (APPNING 2018) held after the ISMRM conference in Paris. It was a well run workshop highlighting the benefits and troubles with large scale animal population imaging&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear Models</title>
      <link>/post/linear-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/linear-models/</guid>
      <description>Introduction library(tidyverse) library(matlib) library(knitr) library(RColorBrewer) The purpose of this document is to understand the parameter and residuals error estimates in a basic linear regression model when working with binary categorical&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An overfit representation of ICLR 2018</title>
      <link>/post/an-overfit-representation-of-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/an-overfit-representation-of-i/</guid>
      <description>I was recently extremely fortunate to attend ICLR 2018, albeit as something of an interloper. Accordingly, what follows is surely a rather atypical highlight reel. All pedantry and any inaccuracy is, of course, due to my own limited understanding of these elegant topics and the breadth of their&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Relative Volumes Matter</title>
      <link>/post/why-relative-volumes-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/why-relative-volumes-matter/</guid>
      <description>Intro Figuring out how one group’s brain is different from another’s is a big part of neuroscience. MRI-neuroanatomy – the study of the sizes of brain regions – is a wonderful tool for this job and makes up a sizeable chunk of what we study. MRI operates in a lovely middle ground in the scales of&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preferential Spatial Gene Expression in Neuroanatomy</title>
      <link>/post/preferential-spatial-gene-expr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/preferential-spatial-gene-expr/</guid>
      <description>Intro In this post I will demonstrate how to use my package ABIgeneRMINC to download, read and analyze mouse brain gene expression data from the Allen Brain Institute. The Allen Brain Institute (ABI) has acquired and released genome-wide spatial gene expression maps for the mouse&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-Clinical Trials</title>
      <link>/post/coclinical-trials/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/coclinical-trials/</guid>
      <description>Why co-clinical trials? Here at the Mouse Imaging Centre, a large portion of our research is related to neurodevelopmental disorders. Ultimately the goal of such research is to improve health outcomes for individuals with these disorders. One clear way to impact health outcomes for individuals with neurodevelopmental disorders is to develop new&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding and playing with peaks in RMINC</title>
      <link>/post/finding-and-playing-with-peaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/finding-and-playing-with-peaks/</guid>
      <description>So, peaks. When producing a statistical map, it’s good to get a report of the peaks (i.e. most significant findings). RMINC has had this support for a while now, though it has remained somewhat hidden. Here’s a bit of an intro,&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Model Selection with PSIS-LOO</title>
      <link>/post/bayesian-model-selection-with-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bayesian-model-selection-with-/</guid>
      <description>Pitch In this post I’d like to provide an overview of Pareto-Smoothed Importance Sampling (PSIS-LOO) and how it can be used for bayesian model selection. Everything I discuss regarding this technique can be found in more detail in Vehtari, Gelman, and Gabry&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear Models</title>
      <link>/post/linear-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/linear-models/</guid>
      <description>Preamble The purpose of this post is to elucidate some of the concepts associated with statistical linear models. Let’s start by loading some&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>StanCon Highlights</title>
      <link>/post/stancon-highlights/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/stancon-highlights/</guid>
      <description>Hi readers, Recently I got back from StanCon 2018 Ansilomar. I had a little time waiting for one of my flights and I thought I’d reflect on the conference. Last year I was lucky enough to go to the first StanCon and it was nice to be able to see how the conference has grown. This year it was three days of tutorials, talks, and networking. I had a&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>/post/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Hello World! Welcome to the new Mouse Imaging Centre Blog. We created this blog as a place to share things we’ve been thinking about lately. This blog will feature a mixture of technical writing about things we do in our lab including imaging, statistics, and biology. The blog will feature contributions from our staff, students, and PIs. We hope you enjoy our&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>