<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on {&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;data sc&lt;/span&gt;r&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;bers}</title>
    <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on {&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;data sc&lt;/span&gt;r&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;bers}</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Modes Using Kernel Density Estimates</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/finding-modes-using-kernel-den/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/finding-modes-using-kernel-den/</guid>
      <description>First, lets do this in R. Need some values to work with. Plot the density estimate with the mode location. Lets do something similar in Python. Start by generating a set of random values. Plot to show indeed we have it right. Note we sort the values first so the PDF looks&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tensorflow</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/tensorflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/tensorflow/</guid>
      <description>This post is my attempt to fill this gap. Rather than focusing on a specific task, I take a more general approach, and explain the fundamental abstractions underpinning Tensorflow. With a good grasp of these concepts, deep learning with Tensorflow becomes intuitive and straightforward. Most Python libraries are written to be natural extensions of&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R4DS June Challenge</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/r4ds-june-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/r4ds-june-challenge/</guid>
      <description>No, however you are still encouraged to work through a book or course and share what you’ve learned on Twitter by using the #SoDS18 hashtag. No, but consider reaching out to the Python for Data Science&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing altair, an R interface to the Altair Python Package</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/introducing-altair-an-r-interf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/introducing-altair-an-r-interf/</guid>
      <description>Introducing altair, an R package to work with the Python package Altair, which you can use to build and render Vega-Lite chart-specifications: https://vegawidget.github.io/altair Vega-Lite offers an implementation of an interactive grammar of graphics. The vocabulary and syntax of this grammar is different from that used by&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to vegawidget</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/welcome-to-vegawidget/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/welcome-to-vegawidget/</guid>
      <description>The effort to bring Vega-Lite to the R community is collaborative; so it appropriate that the altair package be hosted by an organization. The altair R package uses the Altair Python package to create Vega-Lite specifications for interactive charts. This group is named vegawidget, after the altair::vegawidget() function, which is used to render Vega and Vega-Lite chart specifications into&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yet Another Caret Workshop</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/yet-another-caret-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/yet-another-caret-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Intro Yesterday I gave a workshop on applied predictive modelling1 with caret at the 1st LSE Computational Social Science hackathon. Organiser privileges. I put together some introductory code and started a simple GitHub repo for the participants, so I thought I’d share it here as&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stan Basics</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/stan-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/stan-basics/</guid>
      <description>I attended a great short course on bayesian workflow using Stan at the New England Statistics Symposium yesterday. If you don’t know, Stan is “a state-of-the-art platform for statistical modeling and high-performance statistical computation”. You can easily interface with Stan through R (or python or a bunch of other&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kaggle panel recap</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/kaggle-panel-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/kaggle-panel-recap/</guid>
      <description>Short answer: Twitter. I don’t always tweet about career transitions in data science, but I do keep my Twitter bio section pretty focused on what I do and how I got there: Short answer: sheer dumb luck. Long answer: I “found” data science when I was at an incredibly low point in my&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YMMV: non-profit data science</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/ymmv-nonprofit-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/ymmv-nonprofit-data-science/</guid>
      <description>Feeling inspired by some recent data science collaborations, on Friday I released the following tweet into the wild: Publicly it seemed to garner a good deal of positive attention, although I did also receive some valid criticism via&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September 2018 datascience goals</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/september-2018-datascience-goa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/september-2018-datascience-goa/</guid>
      <description>Last updated: 2018-09-03 I know, I know, my last post was 2 months ago. I’m not very steady but lots have been done on other things (FOSS4G-fr 2018 program, a bread recipe that I can manage, writing a python course from scratch, that kind of things). Next step in my life will be in September at the end of my Master degree. I don’t know what I will do at that time but I know what I want to&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Something Different</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/something-different/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/something-different/</guid>
      <description>title: ‘Something Different: Automated Neighborhood Traffic Monitoring’ author: David McGaughey date: ‘2018-03-03’ slug: traffic-monitoring-intro categories: - R - python - raspberry - pi tags: - R - python - raspberry - pi — This is, obviously, a personal project. Traffic is a concern in my town. Cut-through, speeding,&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>liftr (Rmarkdown using docker)</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/liftr-rmarkdown-using-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/liftr-rmarkdown-using-docker/</guid>
      <description>I recently discover a R package, called liftr package. It allows the build of pdf document (and html files, but i didn&amp;rsquo;t test it) from a Rmarkdown file. Fully integrated in RStudio, the R code is executed (and other code as well, I tried python) and results are displayed. You don&amp;rsquo;t even need to have LaTeX on your computer, since the document compilation take place in a docker&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish Stopwords for tidytext package</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/spanish-stopwords-for-tidytext/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/spanish-stopwords-for-tidytext/</guid>
      <description>A clever friend of mine says: the main programming language, is not Java or Python but English. So, when you&amp;rsquo;re searching for help, you&amp;rsquo;ll be much successful if searching in english. The main docs are in english, and if the topic is a bit obscure or not mainstream, you&amp;rsquo;ll be lucky if there&amp;rsquo;s some documents even in&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice for non-traditional data scientists</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/advice-for-nontraditional-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/advice-for-nontraditional-data/</guid>
      <description>I have a pretty strange background for a data scientist. In my career I’ve sold electric razors, worked on credit derivatives during the 2008 financial crash, written market reports on orthopaedic biomaterials, and practiced law. I started programming in R during law school, partly as a way to learn more about data visualization and partly to help analyze youth criminal justice&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First post !</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/first-post-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/first-post-/</guid>
      <description>First of all, welcome to this site ! As the about says, this blog purpose is to talking about OpenGIS, Python, R, data nalysis and stuff like that. I will be probably publishing learning notebooks as i do them to improve my knowledge. When possible, I&amp;rsquo;ll publish original stuff, depends on current affairs. Cheers </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combining R and Python for data analysis</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/combining-r-and-python-for-dat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/combining-r-and-python-for-dat/</guid>
      <description>The main drawback of doing it this way is that I am losing on the interactive explorative tools included in HyperSpy. For this reason my workflow has been to interactively explore and develop the Python code in a Jupyter Notebook, and then copy the final script to a Python chunk in an R Markdown&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>janitor, a good R package for Data Wrangling</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/janitor-a-good-r-package-for-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/janitor-a-good-r-package-for-d/</guid>
      <description>We all know the many hours spent cleaning and wrangling data. Sometimes I think my actual job is not “Data Scientist” but “Data Cleaner”. Data, as you surely know, is not often in the best shape, so for many people like me, one of the most appreciated tools is the one that makes cleaning&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Processing mail using R</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/processing-mail-using-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/processing-mail-using-r/</guid>
      <description>After a long time seeking for R packages to connect to a remote mailbox (not Gmail), I’ve had to admit that there’s no such feature right now in R. Tested a pair of Python scripts but too much convoluted to my needs. It’s an incredible issue that having more than 10 thousand packages available on CRAN, none of them was suitable for my&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking different implementations of weighted-ALS matrix factorization</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/benchmarking-different-impleme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/benchmarking-different-impleme/</guid>
      <description>updated 01/08/2017 - added CG solver in reco, adjusted results As I promised in last post, I’m going to share benchmark of different implementation of matrix factorization with Weighted Alternating Least Squares. User-Item interaction matrix is made from lastfm-360K&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python with Jon Wayne Parrott</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/python-with-jon-wayne-parrott/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/python-with-jon-wayne-parrott/</guid>
      <description>Jon Wayne focuses on the Python developer experience for Google Cloud Platform. He’s an active contributor to multiple open-source Python&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R for Excel Users</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/r-for-excel-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/r-for-excel-users/</guid>
      <description>Like most people, I first learned to work with numbers through an Excel spreadsheet. After graduating with an undergraduate philosophy degree, I somehow convinced a medical device marketing firm to give me a job writing Excel reports on the orthopedic biomaterials&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bigtable with Ian Lewis</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/bigtable-with-ian-lewis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/bigtable-with-ian-lewis/</guid>
      <description>Ian is a Developer Advocate on the Google Cloud Platform team working out of Tokyo. Ian loves Python and Go and helps run the largest Python event in Japan, PyCon JP. Ian is also interested in Docker and Kubernetes and hopes to help Google Cloud Platform users achieve their highest potential. Resources: How to limit what users can do on the resources of your&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cloud In Africa with Hiren Patel and Dale Humby</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/the-cloud-in-africa-with-hiren/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/the-cloud-in-africa-with-hiren/</guid>
      <description>DevOps engineer with a long history of system administration. Currently spending all my time doing a mix of backend development on GCP with python, web frontend development, and some android mobile&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>text2vec GloVe implementation details</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/text2vec-glove-implementation-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/text2vec-glove-implementation-/</guid>
      <description>Before reading this post, I very recommend to read: Orignal GloVe paper Jon Gauthier&amp;rsquo;s post, which provides detailed explanation of python implementation. This post helps me a lot with C++ implementation. Word embeddings After Tomas Mikolov et al. released word2vec tool, there was a boom of articles about words vector&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GloVe vs word2vec revisited.</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/glove-vs-word2vec-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/glove-vs-word2vec-revisited/</guid>
      <description>Today I will start to publish series of posts about experiments on english wikipedia. As I said before, text2vec is inspired by gensim - well designed and quite efficient python library for topic modeling and related NLP tasks. Also I found very useful Radim&amp;rsquo;s posts, where he tried to evaluate some algorithms on english wikipedia dump. This dataset is rather&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locality Sensitive Hashing in R</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/locality-sensitive-hashing-in-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/locality-sensitive-hashing-in-/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the next series of posts I will try to explain base concepts Locality Sensitive Hashing technique. Note, that I will try to follow general functional programming style. So I will use R&amp;rsquo;s Higher-Order Functions instead of traditional R&amp;rsquo;s *apply functions family (I suppose this post will be more readable for non R users). Also I will use brilliant pipe operator %&amp;gt;% from magrittr&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>