<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Medgadgetcom on {data-scribers}</title>
    <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/tags/medgadgetcom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Medgadgetcom on {data-scribers}</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/tags/medgadgetcom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>FutureMed Day 4 - Philip Low, Andrew Hessel, a Visit to Intuitive Surgical, and More</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/futuremed-day-4-philip-low-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/futuremed-day-4-philip-low-and/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday we finished another exceptional 14 hours of medicine, complete with regenerative biology, cutting edge neuroscience, a trip to go play with da Vinci surgical robots and a paranoia-inducing talk on how the future of synthetic biology will present tremendous challenges and opportunities for the world&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FutureMed Day 3 - Robert Hariri, Mike West, a Visit to Autodesk, and More</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/futuremed-day-3-robert-hariri-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/futuremed-day-3-robert-hariri-/</guid>
      <description>We’ve just wrapped up day three and FutureMed is quickly joining the club of highest quality conferences we’ve attended&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FutureMed Day 2 - Eric Schadt, Ester Dyson, a Tour of Kaiser&#39;s Innovation Center, and More</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/futuremed-day-2-eric-schadt-es/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/futuremed-day-2-eric-schadt-es/</guid>
      <description>Day two of FutureMed was just about as dense (8am – 10pm) as day one, with the morning dedicated to the future of personalized medicine, the afternoon to a visit to Kaiser’s Garfield Innovation Center, and then the post-dinner lectures on integrative medicine. On the whole it was a wonderfully inspiring day full of mind-blowing medical advances&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Under Construction...</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/under-construction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/under-construction/</guid>
      <description>Dear Readers,
We&amp;rsquo;ve been experiencing technical difficulties while upgrading Medgadget. We had to roll back a couple of days, but are working on fixing the bugs and getting back to business. We apologize for any inconvenience and hope you stay with us as we try to get through this&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FutureMed Day 1 - Ray Kurzweil, Gabor Forgacs, Eythor Bender, and More</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/futuremed-day-1-ray-kurzweil-g/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/futuremed-day-1-ray-kurzweil-g/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re here at Singularity University&amp;rsquo;s FutureMed after a dense day of exploring mind-melding medical advances&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abbott FreeStyle InsuLinx Blood Glucose Monitoring System with Insulin Calculator Receives CE Mark</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/abbott-freestyle-insulinx-bloo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/abbott-freestyle-insulinx-bloo/</guid>
      <description>Abbott has received CE approval for its FreeStyle InsuLinx Blood Glucose Monitoring System, which, in addition to measuring blood glucose, calculates suggested insulin doses. Calculating appropriate mealtime insulin doses based on blood glucose level and carbohydrate intake can be a challenging task for some patients&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biomagnetics Announces the First Urine-Based Test for Tuberculosis</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/biomagnetics-announces-the-fir/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/biomagnetics-announces-the-fir/</guid>
      <description>Traditional tuberculosis testing can take days to return a result, and, while newer PCR tests can deliver results in a matter of hours, they are much more expensive&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bioness NESS L300 Plus System Gets Green Light in U.S.</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/bioness-ness-l300-plus-system-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/bioness-ness-l300-plus-system-/</guid>
      <description>Bioness out of Valencia, California has received U.S. FDA approval for its NESS L300 Plus System, a combination of the NESS L300 Foot Drop System with a thigh stimulation device&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electromechanical Wave Imaging Non-Invasively Maps Electrical Activation of the Heart</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/electromechanical-wave-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/electromechanical-wave-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Researchers from Columbia Engineering School developed a new method to non-invasively map the electrical activation of the heart. The technique, called Electromechanical Wave Imaging (EWI), uses ultrasound waves to detect very small deformations following the electrical activation of the heart&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For Our Readers</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/for-our-readers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/for-our-readers/</guid>
      <description>Futuremed kicked off this morning at NASA&amp;rsquo;s Ames Research Park and all the attendees will be getting copies of Thinklabs Medical&amp;rsquo;s iMurmur 2 and Heart Record apps for iPhone and iPad&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Program Predicts Salmonella Levels in Pork</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/new-program-predicts-salmonell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/new-program-predicts-salmonell/</guid>
      <description>Warning: don&amp;rsquo;t read the following if you&amp;rsquo;ve recently dined on pig! A new program developed by the UK&amp;rsquo;s Institute of Food Research, the US Department of Agriculture, and Australia&amp;rsquo;s Food Safety Centre seeks to predict the amount of Salmonella present on different levels of the pork supply&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sanofi Pasteur&#39;s Fluzone Intradermal Flu Vaccine Approved in U.S.</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/sanofi-pasteurs-fluzone-intrad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/sanofi-pasteurs-fluzone-intrad/</guid>
      <description>Sanofi won FDA approval for Fluzone Intradermal flu vaccine system. Indicated for ages 18 through 64, the system uses a microinjection needle to deliver the vaccine into the dermis&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study Finds That iPhone App Can Make Accurate Stroke Diagnosis</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/study-finds-that-iphone-app-ca/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/study-finds-that-iphone-app-ca/</guid>
      <description>Researchers from the University of Calgary have shown that doctors can make a stroke diagnosis using an iPhone application just as accurately (and faster) than they can on a traditional&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Cambridge Professor Explains Human Brain Network With Twitter</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/university-of-cambridge-profes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/university-of-cambridge-profes/</guid>
      <description>Ed Bullimore, a professor at the University of Cambridge, recently gave a talk to an audience of eager Britons about the amazing complexity of the brain&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medtronic&#39;s Attain Ability Plus and Attain Ability Straight Left-Heart ICD Leads Now Available in US</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/medtronics-attain-ability-plus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/medtronics-attain-ability-plus/</guid>
      <description>Medtronic has received FDA regulatory approval to market a pair of left ventricle cardiac resynchronization leads&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>