<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jakekauppcom on DATA SCrIbers</title>
    <link>/tags/jakekauppcom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jakekauppcom on DATA SCrIbers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/jakekauppcom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>tidytuesday I&#39;m gonna be...</title>
      <link>/post/tidytuesday-im-gonna-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/tidytuesday-im-gonna-be/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been having some days! Between sick kids, myself getting sick, deadlines and development promises, I haven’t had a lot of time to make any kind of blog post. I have been following along with my #tidytuesday analysis and visualization though, so this week you get a double feature! First up is last weeks Australian tax</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TidyTuesday: The Sad Story</title>
      <link>/post/tidytuesday-the-sad-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/tidytuesday-the-sad-story/</guid>
      <description>This weeks #TidyTuesday is all about global mortality rates. I’ve looked at datasets like this before, and while they are a great way to see interesting trends and practise some visualization skills, I think there is another lesson to be learned. The human element of data. These data were people. They meant something to someone. They were here, now they are</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TidyTuesday</title>
      <link>/post/tidytuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/tidytuesday/</guid>
      <description>I do not update this site as much as I would like. Interacting through twitter and the #R4DS slack channel has been my main contributions as of late to being more active in the #rstats community. I make plans to get to things like posting, then end up with other work, a neat idea, or just decide spend time with my family. Worthy endeavors all of them. Anyways, Thomas Mock (@thomasmock), has started up #tidytuesday out of the mentorship pilot program in</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second star to the right and straight on &#39;til morning</title>
      <link>/post/second-star-to-the-right-and-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/second-star-to-the-right-and-s/</guid>
      <description>The strength of R doesn’t lie in a single programming paradigm, it lies within the warm, welcoming and ecclectic community of useRs. Like anyone who gets introduced to R, you start to look on the web for other like minded people. Upon doing so, you find a vibrant community with very knowledgeable and helpful people. Bob Rudis (@hrbrmstr) is one of those people, doling out R wisdom, visualization, typography, culinary and infosec goodness on the</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEA Reflections</title>
      <link>/post/ceea-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ceea-reflections/</guid>
      <description>Yes, I get it. I don&amp;rsquo;t post often enough. I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to change that though, and overhaul things around here, for a few reasons. Better place to showcase my own work A place for professional reflection Interaction with the rstats and visualization communities Personal portfolio Since I was last here my kids have grown (!), my wife and I continue on the parenting journey (whee!), I launched my consulting career</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>