<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jakekauppcom on {&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;data sc&lt;/span&gt;r&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;bers}</title>
    <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/tags/jakekauppcom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jakekauppcom on {&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;data sc&lt;/span&gt;r&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#39;color:red&#39;&gt;bers}</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/tags/jakekauppcom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>tidytuesday I&#39;m gonna be...</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/tidytuesday-im-gonna-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/tidytuesday-im-gonna-be/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been having some days! Between sick kids, myself getting sick, deadlines and development promises, I haven’t had a lot of time to make any kind of blog post. I have been following along with my #tidytuesday analysis and visualization though, so this week you get a double feature! First up is last weeks Australian tax&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TidyTuesday: The Sad Story</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/tidytuesday-the-sad-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/tidytuesday-the-sad-story/</guid>
      <description>This weeks #TidyTuesday is all about global mortality rates. I’ve looked at datasets like this before, and while they are a great way to see interesting trends and practise some visualization skills, I think there is another lesson to be learned. The human element of data. These data were people. They meant something to someone. They were here, now they are&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#TidyTuesday</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/tidytuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/tidytuesday/</guid>
      <description>I do not update this site as much as I would like. Interacting through twitter and the #R4DS slack channel has been my main contributions as of late to being more active in the #rstats community. I make plans to get to things like posting, then end up with other work, a neat idea, or just decide spend time with my family. Worthy endeavors all of&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second star to the right and straight on &#39;til morning</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/second-star-to-the-right-and-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/second-star-to-the-right-and-s/</guid>
      <description>The strength of R doesn’t lie in a single programming paradigm, it lies within the warm, welcoming and ecclectic community of useRs. Like anyone who gets introduced to R, you start to look on the web for other like minded people. Upon doing so, you find a vibrant community with very knowledgeable and helpful&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CEEA Reflections</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/ceea-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/ceea-reflections/</guid>
      <description>Yes, I get it. I don&amp;rsquo;t post often enough. I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to change that though, and overhaul things around here, for a few&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>52Vis - Homeless</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/52vis-homeless/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/52vis-homeless/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve a confession to make. I&amp;rsquo;m a terrible blogger. I do so out of need and interest, and I&amp;rsquo;ve a lot of the latter but little of the former. &amp;ldquo;The game has changed.&amp;rdquo; Clu (Yes, Tron Returns. Get over it.) Bob Rudis, @hrbrmstr, a useR, visualization practitioner, data-driven security expert, blogger has constructed a wonderful set of information visualization challenges for the next&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goofus and Gallant: Charts</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/goofus-and-gallant-charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/goofus-and-gallant-charts/</guid>
      <description>For the past couple of years I&amp;rsquo;ve been delving into the world of information visualization. Part due to intense interest, part due to job responsibilities. I&amp;rsquo;ve read a lot, taken a lot of courses, and have been working to polish my skills along the&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IVMOOC Reflections</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/ivmooc-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/ivmooc-reflections/</guid>
      <description>So IVMOOC has been over for quite some time now. Looking back on the experience, I consider it to be a personal success. The first half of the course was interesting, and gave a good space for practise with tools and refinement of the skill set needed for&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#IVMOOC Week 7</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/ivmooc-week-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/ivmooc-week-7/</guid>
      <description>Due to the nature of this week in the course, I&amp;rsquo;ve created my visualization and reflection using R, shinyapps.io and various wonderful packages. You can find my reflection and submission&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I don&#39;t have a clever title</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/i-dont-have-a-clever-title/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/i-dont-have-a-clever-title/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m in Boston, in the middle of training for marking of the Critical Thinking Assessment Test. The training is good, and their process is solid. Put that on top of a decent reliable and valid instrument and you&amp;rsquo;ve got something. I&amp;rsquo;ll need to see the results and the data to draw more conclusions, but so far I like it. Anyways&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My business is with R tonight, with maps and color. #IVMOOC Week 5</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/my-business-is-with-r-tonight-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/my-business-is-with-r-tonight-/</guid>
      <description>So the midterm has me a bit disheartened. Not because of difficulty, but because of the miscommunication between the admin and the students. In Canvas the midterm description was set to Feb 16th 8pm EST deadline. After putting my son to bed, and while making dinner, I logged into Canvas and rushed to do the midterm. Flying through it, I ended up with a&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ll take &#39;Famous Titles&#39; for $400 Alex.  #IVMOOC Week 4</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/ill-take-famous-titles-for-400/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/ill-take-famous-titles-for-400/</guid>
      <description>Two posts in week, and two weeks of #IVMOOC down! Topical analysis this week, and keeping in theme, here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where in the world is Carmen Sandiego?</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/where-in-the-world-is-carmen-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/where-in-the-world-is-carmen-s/</guid>
      <description>Getting through this week was a bit tough, not due to content or complexity, but due to life, work and winter. Being the only well parent is a lot of work. Couple that with deadlines, grant writing and research sessions made for very little free time. I made it though! After watching the videos and hands-on clips for the week, I felt tackling this assignment was pretty&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#IVMOOC Week 2</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/ivmooc-week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/ivmooc-week-2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m liking this course. The videos are easy to listen to and are in nice manageable chunks that I can watch them while making dinner, or on a quick break from work. I especially liked the discussion of the burst-detection model this week, although I would have enjoyed a more in-depth discussion on how the model&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#IVMOOC Week 1</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/ivmooc-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/ivmooc-week-1/</guid>
      <description>So I&amp;rsquo;ve made it through the first week of #IVMOOC. Gold stars all around! I did learn some new things, new tricks and new tools from the lectures and I&amp;rsquo;m a sucker for a good framework. Anything that can help me organize chaos in a logical, well though out manner appeals to the engineer in&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you still there?</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/are-you-still-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/are-you-still-there/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes a simple pause leads to a time-out. Juggling parenthood, my normal hatrack of jobs, plus teaching put way to many demands on my time to devote it to #dalmooc, despite it being a very interesting experience. I kept up viewing some hangouts and videos when I could, but didn&amp;rsquo;t devote any effort to the assignments and community&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pressing pause</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/pressing-pause/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/pressing-pause/</guid>
      <description>Dear #Dalmooc, Unfortunately, I have to press pause for some time on my learning to tackle deadlines, wrap up teaching and evaluate my students and my teaching. Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to catch up before the deadlines for the early competencies. We now return you to your regularly scheduled program, already in progress&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of data and questions</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/of-data-and-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/of-data-and-questions/</guid>
      <description>This post was for the 2nd week of #DALMOOC A concept/process mash up of a map. How I think the data sources of student learning can be collected at different levels within an institution, and the giant question mark of how analytics and data visualization can best be used for data-driven program and curriculum improvement, and to enhance the quality of teaching and&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barriers &amp; Analytics</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/barriers-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/barriers-analytics/</guid>
      <description>This post is addressing the first assignment/question for #DALMOOC Analytics use at this organization is largely focused on academic analytics, using the results of assessment of student learning to inform course, program and curriculum&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Affectively effective</title>
      <link>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/affectively-effective/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://data-scribers.mikewk.com/post/affectively-effective/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d like to consider myself as a self-directed, life-long learner. Rather, I would now after undergrad, grad school with a plethora of job related learning thrown in. I didn&amp;rsquo;t start that way, I had to learn. I had to create my own meaning, develop the regulation, control my own motivation, deal with my own setbacks, reflect on my learning, reflect on my&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>