<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lbusettnetlifycom on rscribers</title>
    <link>/tags/lbusettnetlifycom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lbusettnetlifycom on rscribers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/lbusettnetlifycom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MODIStsp approved on rOpenSci!</title>
      <link>/post/modistsp-approved-on-ropensci/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/modistsp-approved-on-ropensci/</guid>
      <description>We are happy to report that our MODIStsp package for automatic preprocessing of MODIS time series has been recently approved for being included in the rOpenSci ecosystem of R packages for reproducible science! We wish to thank reviewers Leah Wasser and Jeffrey Hanson for providing really valuable insights during the onboarding review&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MODIStsp v. 1.3.4 is out ! Now allowing interactive definition of processing extent!</title>
      <link>/post/modistsp-v-134-is-out-now-allo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/modistsp-v-134-is-out-now-allo/</guid>
      <description>We are happy to report that a new version of MODIStsp (1.3.4) is on CRAN as of today ! The new version introduces a strongly improved GUI (thanks mainly to @lwasser comments in her review for MODIStsp onboarding on ropensci ). The new GUI facilitates the selection of layers to be processed, and allows interactive selection of the processing spatial extent over a map (thanks to @timsalabim and @timelyportfolio for implementing some changes on mapview to allow&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new RStudio addin to facilitate inserting tables in Rmarkdown documents</title>
      <link>/post/a-new-rstudio-addin-to-facilit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-new-rstudio-addin-to-facilit/</guid>
      <description>In the last months, I started increasingly using Rmd documents for preparing scientific reports, blog posts, etcetera. While I really like the flexibility offered by the system, one thing that I thought could be improved is the support for easily inserting&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speeding up spatial analyses by integrating `sf` and `data.table`</title>
      <link>/post/speeding-up-spatial-analyses-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/speeding-up-spatial-analyses-b/</guid>
      <description>The problem Last week, I replied to this interesting question posted by @Tim_K over&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MODIStsp 1.3.3 is out - Speeding things up and squashing some bugs !</title>
      <link>/post/modistsp-133-is-out-speeding-t/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/modistsp-133-is-out-speeding-t/</guid>
      <description>A new version of MODIStsp (1.3.3) is on CRAN as of today ! Below, you can find a short description of the main improvements. Processing speed improvements Processing of MODIS layers after download (i.e., scale and offset calibration, computation of Spectral Indexes and Quality Indicators) is now much faster . As you can see in the figure, processing time was almost halved on my (not so fast)&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The new MODIStsp website (based on pkgdown) is online !</title>
      <link>/post/the-new-modistsp-website-based/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-new-modistsp-website-based/</guid>
      <description>The MODIStsp website, which lay abandoned since several months on github pages, recently underwent a major overhaul thanks to&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MODIStsp (v 1.3.2) is on CRAN !</title>
      <link>/post/modistsp-v-132-is-on-cran-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/modistsp-v-132-is-on-cran-/</guid>
      <description>We are glad to report that MODIStsp is now also available on CRAN ! From now on, you can therefore install it by simply using: install.packages(&amp;ldquo;MODIStsp&amp;rdquo;) In v 1.3.2 we also added the functionality to automatically apply scale and offset coefficients on MODIS original values according with the specifications of single MODIS&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>