<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jessemaegancom on DATA SCrIbers</title>
    <link>/tags/jessemaegancom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jessemaegancom on DATA SCrIbers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/jessemaegancom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R4DS (v1 &amp; v2)</title>
      <link>/post/r4ds-v1-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r4ds-v1-v2/</guid>
      <description>As all amazing opportunities in my life are wont to do, it started with a tweet: It’s rare that I find myself dealing with imposter syndrome, but I did spend Thursday night eating all of my feelings of doubt and&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Learn</title>
      <link>/post/learning-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/learning-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>As we head out on this adventure, there’s nothing I’d love more than to hear what’s working for you, what you think could be improved, and what should be left on the cutting room&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When in doubt, optimize for joy</title>
      <link>/post/when-in-doubt-optimize-for-joy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/when-in-doubt-optimize-for-joy/</guid>
      <description>My summer started with a bang: The direction the world was pushing me towards and the direction that I wanted to go in were firmly at odds. So I took the advice of a friend on Slack who, whenever someone posed an even remotely existential question, responded with: And so I made list after list of the things I was involved in, and I began to ever more ruthlessly chop things from the list that did not bring me&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R4DS June Challenge</title>
      <link>/post/r4ds-june-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r4ds-june-challenge/</guid>
      <description>No, however you are still encouraged to work through a book or course and share what you’ve learned on Twitter by using the #SoDS18 hashtag. No, but consider reaching out to the Python for Data Science&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R4DS May Challenge</title>
      <link>/post/r4ds-may-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r4ds-may-challenge/</guid>
      <description>Sure, we could do something similar to the first iteration of our online learning community and say we’re going to cover a specified amount of material each week, but instead we’re going to try something new! By signing up for office hours, you are making a commitment to show up during the office hours&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kaggle panel recap</title>
      <link>/post/kaggle-panel-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/kaggle-panel-recap/</guid>
      <description>Short answer: Twitter. I don’t always tweet about career transitions in data science, but I do keep my Twitter bio section pretty focused on what I do and how I got there: Short answer: sheer dumb luck. Long answer: I “found” data science when I was at an incredibly low point in my life. It was 2013, and I had just impulsively moved cross-country (from NYC to Seattle) with a boyfriend I started having second thoughts about the moment we left&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YMMV: non-profit data science</title>
      <link>/post/ymmv-nonprofit-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ymmv-nonprofit-data-science/</guid>
      <description>Feeling inspired by some recent data science collaborations, on Friday I released the following tweet into the wild: Publicly it seemed to garner a good deal of positive attention, although I did also receive some valid criticism via DMs. All of this combined got me thinking about the best way to address sharing (and building) your data science skills by volunteering with a non-profit organization&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R4DS April Challenge</title>
      <link>/post/r4ds-april-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r4ds-april-challenge/</guid>
      <description>Both of these projects are the result of collaborations between Radovan, Burcu, Raul, Rosa, Jake, Thomas, &amp;amp; Ariel, and we’re thrilled to be sharing them with our&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R4DS March Challenge</title>
      <link>/post/r4ds-march-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r4ds-march-challenge/</guid>
      <description>We’re so close to March, which for many of you involves a lot of college basketball. Four of our community members have graciously stepped up to record a 20-30 minute talk on an R4DS-related topic, and they will be developing these over the next few&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So you’ve been asked to make a reprex</title>
      <link>/post/so-youve-been-asked-to-make-a-/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/so-youve-been-asked-to-make-a-/</guid>
      <description>Reprexes are significantly easier to read, as well as copy and paste. This means that the people helping you solve your error(s) are going to spend less time: No one can force you to make a reprex, but they can decide not to answer your question when you don’t provide a&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R4DS February Challenge</title>
      <link>/post/r4ds-february-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r4ds-february-challenge/</guid>
      <description>The challenge is short and sweet this month, and the same for both learners and mentors: Remember: the size of your win isn’t what’s important–everyone’s learning process unfolds at different rates and sizes–what matters is coming together to celebrate everyone’s learning journey within our online&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science with R</title>
      <link>/post/data-science-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/data-science-with-r/</guid>
      <description>It always starts with a DM on Twitter, where someone shares with me their personal data science ambitions, where they currently are in their plans, and then they follow up with a request for me to help them figure out where to go&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R4DS January Challenge</title>
      <link>/post/r4ds-january-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r4ds-january-challenge/</guid>
      <description>I love the start of the New Year for so many reasons, but one of my favorites is the never-ending stream of motivational word art that populates a good 98% of every social media feed for 31 whole days, like so: Then commit to showing up for five minutes a day, five days a week, in the corresponding Slack channel. Feel free to share what you’re learning, as it’s a fantastic way to help others&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R4DS: the next iteration</title>
      <link>/post/r4ds-the-next-iteration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r4ds-the-next-iteration/</guid>
      <description>Like most online learning endeavors, we had a massive surge of interest at the onset, with exponential drop-offs week after week as we progressively worked through each chapter based on an established schedule. Although everyone who messaged me had their own individual reasons for dropping out, the underlying premise was the same: the pace of the group was too&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>