<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jessesadlercom on rscribers</title>
    <link>/tags/jessesadlercom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jessesadlercom on rscribers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/jessesadlercom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing debkeepr</title>
      <link>/post/introducing-debkeepr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/introducing-debkeepr/</guid>
      <description>The economic historian encounters the difficulties of handling non-decimal currencies in two main contexts. In reading through documents that may or may not be primarily economic in nature, the researcher comes across sets of values that need to be manipulated to better understand their&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Year Anniversary</title>
      <link>/post/one-year-anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/one-year-anniversary/</guid>
      <description>In a nice little coincidence this is the 11th post to the blog and pushes my first introductory post to the second page of blog entries. I am looking forward to the next year of continuing to learn more about digital humanities and R and writing about my experiences on this blog, pushing more and more posts to the second page and&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Circles with R</title>
      <link>/post/great-circles-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/great-circles-with-r/</guid>
      <description>At this point, the output is not hugely informative. However, we can confirm that the process of making great circles worked by observing the curvatures of the lines. Notice that the amount of curvature differs according to distance and the bearing of the&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to GIS with R</title>
      <link>/post/introduction-to-gis-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/introduction-to-gis-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the result. We can see that the data is in the format that we are looking for and that the &amp;ldquo;type&amp;rdquo; column has been correctly transformed into&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Network Analysis with R</title>
      <link>/post/introduction-to-network-analys/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/introduction-to-network-analys/</guid>
      <description>Compare this to an adjacency matrix with the same data. We need to start as always by loading the necessary&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geocoding with R</title>
      <link>/post/geocoding-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/geocoding-with-r/</guid>
      <description>The resulting map is rather sparse and does not provide much information, but it gives a good starting point from which to build a more informative map. I now have the necessary data to create a map that will distinguish between the sources of the letters and their destinations and will allow me to show the quantities of letters sent from and received in each&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excel vs R</title>
      <link>/post/excel-vs-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/excel-vs-r/</guid>
      <description>We can save the objects for later use by using the assignment operator and giving the data frames names. Now that we have the data in a better form, we can plot it by making another bar chart. The graph shows a peak in March of 1585 when Antwerp was in an extremely vulnerable position and it was more important than ever that it receive military and monetary assistance from the rebels in&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking about Workflow</title>
      <link>/post/thinking-about-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/thinking-about-workflow/</guid>
      <description>In the spring of 2011, I was in the middle of doing research for my dissertation. I had recently returned from my second extended trip to the archives in the Netherlands and Belgium and had accumulated a ton of notes. I knew that technology had drastically altered the possibilities for research, but the fundamentals of my own workflow were hardly different than they had been when I began undergrad in the early&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>By Way of Introduction</title>
      <link>/post/by-way-of-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/by-way-of-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Concerning, the actual content of this blog, I envision the posts falling into two general categories. In the first place, the blog will be a space for me to discuss the various projects that I am working on, both traditional history projects and those in digital humanities. Emphasis will be on the latter, since it was in the course of working on digital projects that I created this&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>