<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Samabbottcouk on rscribers</title>
    <link>/tags/samabbottcouk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Samabbottcouk on rscribers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/samabbottcouk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>getTBinR 0.5.4 now on CRAN - new data, map updates and a new summary function.</title>
      <link>/post/gettbinr-054-now-on-cran-new-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/gettbinr-054-now-on-cran-new-d/</guid>
      <description>getTBinR 0.5.4 is now on CRAN and should be available on a mirror near you shortly! This update includes an additional data set for 2016 containing variables related to drug resistant Tuberculosis, some aesthetic updates to mapping functionality and a new summarise_tb_burden function for summarising TB metrics. Behind the scenes there has been an extensive test overhaul, with vdiffr being used to test images, and several bugs&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Tuberculosis Monitoring Indicators in England; Using Dimension Reduction and Clustering</title>
      <link>/post/exploring-tuberculosis-monitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/exploring-tuberculosis-monitor/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I recently attended the Public Health Research and Science Conference , run by Public Health England (PHE), at the University of Warwick. I was mainly there to present some work that I have been doing (along with my co-authors) estimating the direct effects of the 2005 change in BCG vaccination policy on Tuberculosis (TB) incidence rates ( slides ) but it was also a great opportunity to see what research is being done within, and partnered with,&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Estimates of the Tuberculosis Case Fatality Ratio - with getTBinR</title>
      <link>/post/exploring-estimates-of-the-tub/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/exploring-estimates-of-the-tub/</guid>
      <description>This is a quick post exploring estimates of the case fatality ratio for Tuberculosis (TB) from data published by the World Health Organisation (WHO). It makes use of getTBinR (which is now on CRAN ), pacman for package management, hrbrthemes for plot themes, and pathwork for combining multiple plots into a&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Global Trends in Tuberculosis Incidence Rates - with GetTBinR</title>
      <link>/post/exploring-global-trends-in-tub/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/exploring-global-trends-in-tub/</guid>
      <description>In November I attended Epidemics , which is a conference focused on modelling infectious diseases. There was a lot of great work and perhaps most excitingly a lot of work being offered as R packages. I’ve recently begun wrapping all my analytical work in R packages, as it makes producing reproducible research a breeze! Unfortunately all of this work is still making it’s way towards publication and for a variety of reasons can’t be shared until it has passed this&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuberculosis Incidence and Interventions in England and Wales, 1913-2016</title>
      <link>/post/tuberculosis-incidence-and-int/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/tuberculosis-incidence-and-int/</guid>
      <description>This interactive dashboard uses data on Tuberculosis incidence from 1913-1916 released by Public Health England and combines it with data on the interventions against Tuberculosis that have been discovered/implemented over the last century. The data was cleaned and imported into R using the tbinenglanddataclean R package, which also contains information on how to apply for additional data, scripts to clean data extracts and graphing functions to visualise&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>